这是美国史上最大的一次现金盗窃
It is the biggest cash robbery in U.S. history--
从一个纽约的装甲车办公室里
$8 million taken
盗窃了8百万
from an armored-car company office in New York City.
昨日
There may have been close
这里将近有3千万
to $30 million here yesterday,
都是现金 大多数都是50和100面值
all in cash, mostly 50s and hundreds.
一队联邦调查局特工小组
A task force of FBI agents
和纽约侦探们都试图解决
and New York City detectives are trying to solve
这个美国史上最大的现金盗窃案
the biggest cash robbery in U.S. history.
联邦调查局和纽约警署
FBI and New York City police investigators
成群结队的穿过 布朗克斯装甲车公司的屋顶
swarmed over the roof of a Bronx armored-truck company
盗贼在屋顶掏了个洞
after thieves cut a hole in the roof
并且成就了美国史上最大的 现金盗窃
and made off with the largest cash theft in U.S. history.
警方指出摄像头指向房预
Police also said that a television camera pointed at the vault
被移动过了 这让人联想到
had been moved, leading to speculation
有内鬼在帮助这些盗贼
that the burglars had inside help.
目前为止还一分钱都没找到
At this point not one penny has been recovered.
但联邦调查局官方表示 他们已经找到一些有用的线索
But FBI officials say they're working on a number of good leads
并且对找回现金信心十足
and are optimistic about finding the money.
如果我知道 我会拿个铲子 掘地三尺
If I knew, I would be out there with a shovel looking for it.
目前我们真的还不知道
We really don't know right at the moment.
埃迪 埃迪 埃迪 埃迪
Eddie, Eddie, Eddie, Eddie.
我有两个问题 埃迪
Two questions for you, Eddie:
克里斯在哪？
Where's Chris?
还有钱在哪？
And where's the money?
[3个月前]
我退出
I quit.
该死的讨厌鬼
Fucking douchebags.
-纳威 你被开除了 -什么？
- Naw, you're fired. - What?
-你被开除了 -不 老兄 是我退出了
- You're fired. - No, bro, I quit.
你不能退出 你每个星期都在某个别的地方退出
You can't quit. You quit every week from somewhere different.
-你被开除了 -没错
- You're fired. - Yeah, that's right.
-我他妈的退出 行吗？ -闭嘴
- Yeah, I fucking quit, all right? - Oh, shut up.
-你被开除了 -什么？你说什么？
- You're fired. - What? What's that?
你想要我捡垃圾？ 要我给你点颜色看看？
Yo, you want me to pick up trash? What fucking color do I look like?
-你就是垃圾 你他妈的 -混蛋
- You are the trash, you little fuck. - Motherfucker.
哟哟哟哟哟
Yo yo yo Yo Y掳-
怎么 你想试试？
What, you want some?
-快滚 快离开这 -怎么样 你他妈的？
- Get going, get outta here. - How about that, you fat fuck?
-快点 -离开走 快走
- Come on. - Get outta here, get going.
-快点 我们走 -你被开除了
- Come on, let's go. - And you're fired!
-你被开除了！ -我退出的 混蛋
- You're fired! - I quit, motherfucker.
不 不 不 你被开除了！
No no no, you're fired!
片名 帝国
搞什么鬼？
Yo, what the fuck?
-那是你的头儿？ -是
- That was your boss? - Yeah.
他想要我清理垃圾桶
Yeah, he wants me to clean up garbage.
然后我就说 哟 你要我再给你点颜色看看 混蛋？
I'm like, "Yo, what color do I look like to you again, asshole?"
我讨厌意大利人 老兄
I hate Italians, bro.
我告诉你 没什么值得让我给意大利人打工
Nothing's worse than working for Italians, let me tell you.
比给意大利人打工还糟的事 就是给希腊人打工
Only thing worse than working for Italians is working for the Greeks,
而且我还不得不回那该死的餐厅工作
and I have to go back and work at that stupid diner again.
扯淡 那家伙就是栽赃嫁祸
Bullshit. The guy's a straight-up douche, bro.
他说他觉得我在偷东西
He's telling me he thinks I'm stealing and stuff.
你说过你偷了
You said you were.
我是偷了 但他还算个 怎么样？
I was, but he's still a dick. How about that?
最糟的就是希腊人
Only thing worse is the Greeks.
嘿 姑娘们 干什么去？
Hey, what's up, ladies?
哟 有没有姑娘
Yo, any of you girls
现在想上我的 我躺下了
wanna do me right now, I'm down.
艾莱尼一定是傻了才会嫁给你 白痴！
Eleni must be real stupid marrying you, idiot!
-去你妈的！ -讨厌鬼
- Suck it! - Douchebag!
*我的肩上有一道彩虹
There's a rainbow over my shoulder
*当你到来 我的心斟满了爱
When you came, my cup runneth over
*你给了我沉甸甸的爱
You gave me your heavenly love
*如果一晚你听到头顶上方的哭泣
And if one night you hear crying from above
*来自天堂
'Cause heaven
*一定是因为遗失了一个天使
Must be missing an angel
*遗失的小天使
Missing one angel child
*因为现在你正与我在一起
Because you're here with me right now
*你的爱如此沉重
Your love is heavenly
*宝贝
Bab)!
*对我来说无比神圣 宝贝
Heavenly to me, baby
*喔...神圣
Oooh, heaven
-*喔 神圣... -凯伦 你的鸡玩够了
- Oooh, heaven... - Enough with the chickens, Karen.
停下别再玩鸡了
You gotta stop with the chickens.
她对鸡都狂热了
She's crazy about the chickens.
-该死的咬我嘴唇 -嘿 来帮把手
- Eh, fucking bit my lip. - Hey, give me a hand with this.
婊子 咬我的嘴巴
Son of a bitch. Bit my lip.
嘿 你真的要跟艾莱尼结婚？
Hey, are you really gonna marry Eleni?
-你怎么跟我妈似的 -你不会跟任何人结婚
- You sound like my mother. - You're not gonna marry nobody.
不为什么 老兄 如果他们想给我做雕塑 我想要把蛋雕大点
Not for nothing, bro, but if they make a statue of me, I want big balls.
-你知道我在说什么吗？ -嘿 妈！
- Know what I'm saying? - Hey, Ma!
-我们给你带礼物了 -这是什么？
- We come bearing gifts. - What's this?
我给你弄了个雕塑... 你一直想要的雕塑
I got you a statue-- the statue you wanted.
-真好 -嘿
- Nice. - Hey.
能亲我一下吗？ 谢谢
Do I get a kiss? Thank you.
-你从哪弄来的这个 -你可以在里面种植物
- Where did you get this? - You could put a plant in it.
-怎么 你不喜欢？ -很好 很好
- What, you don't like it? - It's nice, it's nice.
-把它放那边 -放那边？
- Put it right there. - Put it over here?
-没错 就那边靠墙放 -没问题
- Yeah, right there against the wall. - Okay.
-很好 -我刚要说你要是不喜欢
- Nice. - I'm just saying if you don't like it,
-我们可以拿回去 -我喜欢 我喜欢
- we can take it back. - I like it, I like it!
-很棒 -哪 那边？
- It's nice. - Where, over here?
-你想放这上面？ -波特米提斯夫人...
- You want it on this thing? - Mrs. Potamitis--
-嘿 妈 -小心那些植物
- Hey, Ma. - Please be careful with those plants.
-竖起来 竖起来 -你想放在...
- Stand it up, stand it up. - You want it somewhere...
-你喜欢吗？ -非常好
- You like that? - That's good.
-放好了 怎么样？ -你喜欢吗？
- There we go. How about that? - You like that?
-妈！ -很好 我喜欢 太漂亮了
- Ma! - It's good, I like it. It's beautiful.
那你要我把海龟怎么办？
What do you want me to do with the turtle?
你要我告诉你怎么处理海龟？
Would you like me to tell you what to do with the turtle?
-把它放下 别让他受伤了 -你不喜欢？
- Put it down and don't break it. - You don't like it?
-把它放那 -谢谢 克里斯 非常好
- Put that over there. - Thank you, Chris. It's very nice.
-你喜欢吗 妈？ -谢谢 很喜欢 谢谢
- You like that, Ma? - Thank you, yes, thank you.
-我们把这送你当礼物 -好好好
- We got presents for you. - Good good good.
你真的看起来不错 对吗？ 小心 好吗？
You be good today, all right? Be careful, all right?
你要我再移它 我就过来移
You want me to move it, I move it again.
如果你不喜欢 我们就拿回去
You don't like it, we'll take it back.
-去去去 -你没必要留着它 知道吗？
- Go go go. - You don't have to do it, you know?
好 够了！走吧
All right, enough! Go.
好吧 爱你 妈
Okay, love you, Ma.
嘿 斯皮罗 我爸爸在吗？
Hey, Spiro. My father around?
在厕所里 孩子
In the shitter, kid.
-嘿
- H6Y- - H6Y-
克里斯
Chris.
他们让你在这什么都干 对吗 爸？
They got you doing everything around here, huh, Pop?
是
Yeah.
你知道 能者多劳嘛 对吧？
You know, this is what happens when you have too many skills, right?
那么 你的姑娘呢？
So where's the girl?
我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
我只是过来看看要不要载你回家？
I was just seeing if you need a ride home.
-看看你身体怎么样 -你周五晚上过来这
- You know, checking up on you. - Come in here on a Friday night
-载我回家？ -不 不 我没说...
- to give me a ride home? - No no, I didn't say--
我很担心你 你在做什么？
I'm worried about you. What are you doing?
只是顺路
Just stopping bY
怎么 我一进来 大家都不说话了？
What, I come in, everybody goes quiet?
不 不 我们刚还在聊
No no, we were just talking.
你不喜欢那个混蛋
You don't like that fat asshole
跟你爸爸说话的方式
talking that way about your father.
克里斯不用担心你爸爸
Chris doesn't need to worry about his father.
不 不 你是对的 汤米 抱歉
No no, you're right, Tommy. I'm sorry.
不过我们也同意他确实是个混蛋
But we agree he's a fat asshole though.
我带着敬意来的 他也应该如此
I come here with respect. He should do the same.
敬意 好极了
Respect. Bravo.
敬意...谁在乎？你现在的口气跟你爸一个叛
Respect-- who gives a shit? You sound like your father now.
-嘿 斯皮罗 -汤米 我理解他
- Hey, Spiro. - Now, Tommy, I understand him.
-我知道你什么意思 -把你的手拿开 行吗？
- I know what you're saying. - Get your hands off him, okay?
你他妈的到底在干嘛？搞什么鬼？
What the hell are you doing? What the hell is that?
-哇 -抱歉 好吗？
- Wow. - I'm sorry, okay?
你不用摸他 行吗？
You don't need to touch him.
你在开玩笑吗？他现在在跟我开玩笑吗？
Are you kidding me? Is he kidding me right now?
好吧 我只是...你不用摸他
Okay, just-- you don't need to touch him.
我只是想了解 你不想让我摸你爸爸？
I just want to know, so you don't want me to touch your father?
-你他妈的不用摸他 -斯皮罗！
- You don't need to fucking touch him. - Spiro!
-让他滚出去 -停下 够了！
- Get him outta here. - Stop it, enough!
-你觉得我能摸谁？ -够了 斯皮罗！
- Who you want me to touch? - Enough! Spiro!
-不 没事 没事 -你在干嘛？
- No, it's okay, it's okay. - What are you doing?
我只是想知道他觉得我可以摸谁
I just want to know who it is that I can touch.
-冷静点 放轻松 -哇哇哇
- Just calm down, take it easy. - Whoa whoa whoa.
没事 我们很好 就是这孩子太激动了
It's okay, we're fine. The kid's just excitable.
他没事 很好 只是有点激动
He's all right. It's okay, just got excited.
-他没事 -走
- He'll be okay. - Go.
走 我说了走
Go. I said go now.
我说了走！走！
I said go! Go 90!
这边我来处理
斯皮罗 听着 你是个有能力的人
Spiro, listen, you're a powerful man.
你给了我需要的工作 但是别再在我儿子面前
You gave me a job that I need, but you don't speak with me
那样跟我说话 嗯？
like that in front of my son again, hmm?
否则？
Cr?
否则你就是别再那样
Or you just don't.
那我们但愿如此 好吧 汤米？
Let's hope it doesn't come to that, okay, Tommy?
我们会很好 没问题 他只是还是 对吗？他们太容易激动
We'll be fine, no problems. That's kids, right? They're excitable.
-谢谢 -没事了 没事了
[纽约市警察局]
你好吗？还行吧？
How you doing? Okay?
我很好 你好吗？
Yeah, I'm all right. Are you okay?
我？当然 很好 我很好
Me? Yeah sure, fine. I'm fine.
小薇 多穿点衣服 你怎么回事？
Yo, Vicky, put some clothes on. What's wrong with you?
-嘿 -闭嘴 我只是去看信箱
- Hey. - Shut up, just checking the mail.
-嘿 -妈 你看看小薇穿成什么样子？
- Hey. - Ma, you see what Vicky's wearing?
-管好你自己的事 -闭上你他妈的嘴 克里斯
- Mind your business. - Shut your fucking face, Chris.
嘿 薇多利亚 嘴巴放干净点
Hey, Victoria, watch your mouth.
-穿得跟个乞丐似的 -嘿
- Looks like a tramp dressed like that. - Hey.
克里斯 别那样说你妹妹 快点
Chris, don't talk to your sister like that, come on.
小薇 上楼去 穿好衣服
Vicky, go upstairs, put on a dress or something nice.
没有女孩子会穿别的衣服 爸爸
None of the girls wear dresses any more, Daddy.
我不在乎其他的女孩子穿的乞丐样
I don't care if the other girls dress like tramps.
-托马森 拜托 -穿得正经点
- Thomasos, please. - Gotta dress like a decent person.
-大清早的吵什么？ -我想让她穿好衣服
- It's too early for this. - I want her to dress nice.
-别管她 还有你 -她只穿内衣啊 妈妈
- Leave her alone. And you. - She's got no clothes on, Mom.
我说什么来着 在我的房子里 我连话语权都没有
What'd I say? I can't win. Unbelievable.
难以置信
In my own house.
我知道你不喜欢
I know you hate working
给俱乐部那些混蛋工作 爸
for those jerks at the club, Pop.
没事 一切都很顺利
It's okay. Everything's good.
-你做好你该做的 -是
- You gotta do what you gotta do. - Yeah.
我知道 但是我想帮你
I know. But I want to help.
你知道吗？等我在警察局找到份差事
You know? And when I get this job with the police,
我就可以给全家一个保障 对吗？
I can put the whole family on the insurance, you know?
是啊 我儿子长大了
Yeah. My son the giant.
拜托 爸爸 我是认真的
Come on, Dad. I'm being serious.
我在希腊当警察的时候
You know, when I was a policeman back in Greece,
我逮捕的第一个人是虐待妓女的人
my first arrest was a man beating a chicken.
这是真事
That's a true story.
让你感觉很棒 对吗？
Made you feel good though, right?
-什么 那个妓女？ -拜托 我是认真的
- What, the chicken? - Come on, I'm serious.
-那感觉很棒 对吧？ -我感觉很棒
- It made you feel good though, right? - I felt good.
非常棒
That's good.
那就是我的梦想 我想当警察
It's what I wanna do, you know? I wanna be a cop.
我想做你做过的事 爸爸
I wanna do what you did, Pop.
-这就是我想做的 -好
- It's all I wanna do. - Okay.
你集中精力在这上 这很好 你会成功的
You concentrate on that. That's good. You'll get that.
很好 瞧 现在你穿了...
That's nice. See, now you're wearing...
一些衣服 这很好
some clothes. This is good.
-像个正经姑娘 小姑娘 -没什么
- Like a decent gir-- young lady. - Nothing!
那是一件漂亮的 呃 汗衫
That's a beautiful, uh, shirt.
-是 -很好 小薇！
- Yeah. - That's nice-- Vicky!
该死
Oh shit.
-这是什么？ -一定是通知我去考试的
- What is this? - It must be the date to take the test.
看吧 好消息 这很好
Ah, see, good things. This is good.
[驳回申请]
这一定是在开玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
波特米提斯长官 什么时候考试？
Officer Potamitis, when's the big test?
-我不知道 那混蛋在这吗？ -在后面
- I don't know. Jerk-offs here? - In the back.
-闻起来就一股混蛋味 -嘿 闭上你他妈的嘴 埃迪
- Smells like an open asshole back here. - Hey, shut the fuck up, Eddie.
也许你该重操旧业
Maybe you should be keeping your old job,
如果你不喜欢这的气味 呃？
if you don't like how it smells here, eh?
一股狗屎味 什么事 伙计？
It smells like dogshit. What's up, bro?
你在外面看见迈克的新蒂威车没？
Yo, you see Mike's new DeVille outside
那车有电动液压系统
with the hydraulic system and shit?
还有立体声收录机？ 去他妈的
Stereo cassette? Fuck him.
-是啊 太恶心了 -非常恶心
- Yeah, it's a pussy magnet. - A lot of pussy.
-我有话跟你说 -我？
- I gotta talk with you. - Me?
-快说 -嘿 你在哪弄来的？
- Come on. - Hey, where'd you get that?
史密斯韦斯顿那
Smith and Weston's.
你要关我们进牢房吗 波特米提斯长官？
You gonna turn us in, Officer Potamitis?
别担心 我们只买了哥伦比亚人的保险
Huh? Don't worry, we only use it for Colombian insurance.
告诉他你们从波多黎各人那弄到的东西
Yeah, tell him the shit you got with the Puerto Ricans.
-他妈的 我是认真的... -哥伦比亚人 好吗？
- There's-- it's fucking-- I'm serious. - Colombians, okay?
你什么时候能有钱 埃迪 说真的
And when you have money, Eddie, you're serious.
给你 吃点炸薯条
Until then, here. Have some more fries.
该死
Shit.
-时间到了？ -哥伦比亚人的电话
- Time? - Yeah, speaking of Colombians.
我们得去帕帕加那
We gotta go to Papagalo's.
是吗？赞
Oh yeah? Cool.
好吧 伙计们
All right, boys.
回头见 好吗？
See you boys later, all right?
怎么？他们点的炸薯条
What? What, they got fries.
那些混蛋有的是钱 老兄
Those assholes are swimming in money, bro.
看看我们还在找扯淡的工作... 你还在学习当警察 为了什么？
Look at us looking for bullshit jobs-- you studying to become a cop. For what?
我在试着成就自我的人生
I'm trying to do something with my life.
这只是在浪费时间 因为你就是一傻B
Now a waste of time 'cause you're a stupid shit.
-我怎么了？ -他妈的黑色安息日（乐队）的演唱会
- What did I do? - The fucking Black Sabbath concert.
就因为那个我都不能再申请当警察
Now 'cause of that I can't even apply to be a cop no more.
黑色安息日的演唱会 都是几百万年前的事了 老兄
Black Sabbath concert was like a million years ago, bro.
它还记录在我的档案里 我真他妈的想杀了你
It stayed on my record. I should fucking kill you for it.
-那都是胡扯 老兄 -你以为我不知道？
- It's a fucking joint, bro. - You think I don't know that?
真逊 老兄 抱歉
Yo, that sucks, bro. I'm sorry.
我带你去帕帕加 请你喝酒
Let me take you to Papagalo's, buy you a drink.
-你根本就没钱 -我有钱 来吧
- You ain't got no money. - I got money, come on.
我要去撒尿
I'm gonna go do a piss.
-抱歉 老兄 -行
- Yo, I'm sorry bro. - Yeah.
说真的 逊毙了 老兄
Honestly, that sucks, bro.
-来吧 我请喝酒 -你根本没钱
- Come on, drinks on me. - You ain't got no money.
一会电话我
Call me later.
这雨就是场悲剧
The rain is miserable.
抱歉我迟到了 埃尔先生
Sorry I'm late, Mr. L.
-嘿 南希 -嘿
- Hey, Nance. - Hey.
我看见小薇了 她说 你不能再参加警察考试了？
I saw Vicky. She said you're not taking the cop test no more?
-呃... -因为埃迪？
- Uh... - Because of Eddie?
是啊 你懂的
Yeah, you know.
而且我妈妈也知道 所以
And my mother got a thing for him, so.
-他就是个白痴 -没错
- Yeah, he's an idiot. - Yeah.
好吧 如果你有什么需要
All right, well, if you need anything,
伞或者别的 我就在这
an umbrella or whatever, I'm here.
好 谢谢 南希
Okay, thanks, Nance.
所有我能说的就是我已经拿到 武器执照了
All I can say is I've already got a weapons permit.
可以在晚上 周末 任何你想要的时间工作
I can work nights, weekends, whatever you want.
在我会识字的时候我就跟着军队学习
I've been studying to be with the force since I was old enough to read.
我确定老板会对这点印象深刻的
Yeah, I'm sure the boss would be real impressed with that.
听着 朋友 这不是纽约警察局
Look, my friend, this ain't the NYPD.
我希望你能理解
I hope you can understand that.
是是 我能理解
Yeah yeah, I understand that.
你确定200美元一星期没问题？
And are you okay with the $200 a week?
我在俱乐部的时候 工作一晚50块
Yuh... I was making 50 a night working at a club.
你已经有一份工作了 你可真幸运
Well, you've already got a job! How lucky are you?
嘿 玛丽 让下一个进来 好吗？
Hey, Mary, let's send somebody else up here, okay?
俱乐部关门了 我会做这份工作
Uh, the club closed, so I'll take it.
哦
Oh.
我也这么认为
I thought so.
好吧
Okay then.
欢迎光临
Welcome aboard.
[灵魂训练 时尚]
你在这热吗？
Is it hot enough for you here, huh?
该死的空调居然坏了
Frigging air conditioner ain't working.
他们会修 他们一直跟我说 他们会修
They're gonna fix it. They keep telling me they're gonna fix it,
但是谁他妈的知道？
but who the hell knows?
你要是再继续玩那玩意 那会打爆你的蛋 伙计
You keep playing with that thing, you're gonna blow your balls off, man.
或者更糟 打爆我的
Or worse-- mine.
抱歉 我只是...
Yeah, sorry. I just, uh--
你不敢相信第一天 我们就给你枪 对吧？
You can't believe they gave you a gun on your first day, huh?
是啊 我从没试过真枪射击
Yeah, I mean I never even shot anything before, you know?
记住 防弹背心只保护你的心脏 可不保护你的蛋
Just remember, the vest is for your heart, not your balls, so.
你叫克里斯 对吗？
You're Chris, right?
-是 -是 没错
- Yeah. - Yeah, that's right, yeah yeah.
我叫托尼 我告诉过你了吧
I'm Tony. Well, I told you that already.
还有这是玛丽和吉安娜
And this-- Marie and Giana.
分别是我老婆和我女儿
That's my wife and little girl.
她们是唯一让我开车越过边境的动力
They're the only thing keeping me from driving this over the border.
总之 我们一天做8-10次的装载
So anyways, we do about eight to 10 pick-ups a day.
然后我们开车把它们放回
Then we drive around and drop it off,
开车越久 得到的就越多
drive some more, get some more,
业主会拿走总收入的部分
the owners take some off the top,
然后星期三早上我们回来交储备金
and then Wednesday morning we go back to the Reserve.
完成 漂亮 就像一次大脑手术
Done. Beautiful. Brain surgery.
等等 业主会拿钱？
Wait, the owners are taking money?
是的 这是老板的规矩
Yeah well, it's the bosses' rule,
但事实上 他们能为所欲为
but hell, they can do whatever the hell they want in here.
一大堆骗人的把戏
A lot of monkey business all I know is going on.
总之 知道的太多会把你逼疯
Knowing too much will drive you crazy, anyway.
简单一点就好 做好本职工作
Just keep it simple, do your job,
找个妞 买套房 完事
find a girl, buy a house. Okay.
事情就是这样
So this is how it goes.
我们把钱装起来 把钱跟你一起锁在这后面
We pick the money up, we lock it in the back here with you.
-锁在后面 -我们只能
- Lock in the back. - We're only talking
大约拿8万3
83 grand or so.
就这样 这种袋子一次 能轻松的装25万
That's it. One of these bags can hold 250 easy.
最大的我曾经装过6百万
Biggest load I ever had was six million.
-是不是很疯狂？ -嘿 你不关上...
- It's crazy, huh? - Hey, you want to shut the--
不不不 没事 你站在那边就行
No no no, it's fine. Just stay on your toes.
你留在外面 我很快就出来
You stay out here. I'll be in and out quick.
-嘿 萨尔 -是是
- Hey, Sal! - Yeah yeah.
-怎么 你去理发了？
Oh what, did you get a haircut?
嘿 长官
Hey, officer.
-嘿 小孩 -哇哇哇！
- Hey, kid. - Whoa whoa whoa!
-干嘛 你疯了吗 -哇哇
- What, are you crazy? - Whoa whoa.
你到底怎么回事？
What the hell's the matter with you?
你等着我告诉你爸爸
Wait till I tell your father about this.
-你差点害死你自己 -嘿 伙计
- You could have gotten yourself killed. - Hey, partner.
别让任何人偷偷接近你
Try and not let somebody sneak up on you.
-是是 抱歉抱歉 -没事
- Yeah yeah. Sorry sorry. - Yeah, all right.
当我们在搬运的时候 你要把枪放这
When we're hauling loot, you're gonna be on shotgun duty back here.
-好 放这 -你明白了？
- All right, back here. - You got that?
-是的 -好 很好
- All right. - All right, good.
保护它就好像是你他妈的钱一样
All right, so guard it like it was your mother's 83 grand.
-你要我留在这吗？ -是 随便你干什么
- Want me to stay back here? - Yeah, do what you want.
-好 -袋子里有很多蒜味腊肠
- Okay. - A lot of salami in those bags, huh?
-是啊 真的 -相信我
- Yeah, no kidding. - Trust me when I say
我知道你在后面想什么
I know what you're thinking back there.
相信我 我知道
Trust me, I do.
现金让人疯狂
Cash makes people do some crazy shit.
-你可得保持清醒 -好
- You gotta keep your head about you. - Okay.
后面很热对吗？
It's hot as hell back there, right?
该死
Uh, no shit.
没错 你会适应的 伙计
Yeah well, you'll get used to it, buddy.
听着 今天是我女儿的生日
Listen, it's my daughter's birthday,
我想早点完事回家 好吗？
so I gotta get out of here early, okay?
-好 听起来不错 -当他们在整理袋子的时候
- Okay, sounds good. - While they sort through the bags,
随他们怎样
do whatever the hell they do,
我会带你去熟悉一下流程
I'll walk you through the process.
进来了！
Coming in!
等等 他们不介意你把我一个人 留在那跟钱在一起？
Wait, they're not gonna care that you're leaving me alone to put away the money?
谁 老板？那有一群罪犯
Who, the boss? A bunch of criminals up there.
别担心你自己
Don't worry yourself over it.
我们只做我们的事
We just do our thing up here.
好
Okay,
锁的钥匙
so the keys to the lock up
-就存放在这 -随你怎么说
- are kept right here. - Whatever you say.
最低工资
Minimum wage.
来吧 我给你看点好东西
Come on, I'll show you the good stuff.
但是 这...这样可以吗？
Anyway, this-- this is okay?
我不知道 去问他爸
I don't know. Ask him.
1 2 3 4
One, two, three, four.
他们可真没什么创意
They're not very creative here.
是啊 没错
Yeah, no shit.
就在那了
And there it is.
两干五百万
$25 million.
-那是两千五百万？ -让它们变多点或是变少点
- That's $25 million? - Give or take a couple of 'em.
一百万？
Of a million?!
嘿 哇哇哇
Hey, whoa whoa whoa.
小心 那有摄像头
Watch out. There's a camera right there.
-好吧 -是的
- Oh, okay. - Yeah.
好 所以等他们上楼
Okay, so after they're done upstairs
我们就把它扔这里面 堆放起来直到它变满
we drop it in here, it piles up until it's full.
有半数时候司机不先把它拿上楼
Half the time the drivers don't even bring it upstairs first.
那么他们怎么知道里面有多少？
So how do they know how much is in there?
他们不知道
They don't.
-他们不知道？ -不知道
- They don't? - No.
-所以如果有钱不见了... -如果有钱不见了
- So if some goes missing-- - If some goes missing,
他们也不会第一时间发现的 伙计
it wouldn't be the first time around here, pal.
噢 嘿嘿！
Oh hey hey!
-嘿 快点 -里面有狗？
- Hey, come on. - There's a dog in there?
是啊 里面有狗 过来 这是邦尼
Yeah, there's a dog. Come here, this is Barney.
我忘了...他几乎是全聋的
I forgot to-- he's deaf as a doornail,
-可怜的老家伙 -什么 他住里里面？
- the poor old guy. - What, he lives in that?
他在里面跟钱住在一起 快点 走吧
He lives in there with the money. Come on, go ahead.
-太疯狂的 该死 -回去睡觉
- It's crazy. No shit. - Go back to bed.
哦
Oh.
嘿 又是玛丽打来的 快点
Hey, that's Maria now. Come on.
我得把这锁起来
I gotta lock this up.
记住 你的搭档我可是个 头脑清醒的人
Now remember, your partner here came down with a severe head cold.
-明白 -明白？
- Got it. - All right?
-是 -你帮我把这个放回去
- Yeah. - You gotta get my back on this one.
-明白 -把这些钥匙放回桌子里
- You got it. - Put those keys back behind the desk.
-明天见 -好
- I'll see you tomorrow. - Okay.
该死的狗
Fucking dog.
怎么 你在熬夜工作吗 爸？
Boy, what, are you taking a night off, Pop?
嘿
Hey.
我只是在小憩
No, I was just taking a little break.
对你身体有好处
Well, good for you.
-那边怎么样？ -他们辞了你父亲
- What's going on here? - They let your father go.
-什么？ -10年了 一点提示都没有
- What? - After 10 years, no warning.
-够了 亲爱的 够了 -都是好人 不是吗？
- Enough, dear. Enough, dear. - Nice people, huh?
就因为那晚在厕所发生的事？
What, because of that thing in the bathroom the other night?
-嗯 那当然是原因 -好吧 真的 够了
- Mm-hmm, of course that's why. - It's fine, really, enough.
-就这样 -不 不 这不好
- That's it. - No no, it's not fine.
-他没这个权利 -他是老板 他有权这么做
- He had no right. - He's the boss, he has the right.
不 为什么？就因为 你总是拥护那群混蛋
No. Why? Because you stood up to that jerk-off, that's why?
当然 那群下三滥
Of course that's why. The bunch of hoodlums
-过着罪犯的生活 -够了
- living their lives like criminals. - Enough.
-够了 你们俩 -不 还不够
- Enough, both of you. - No, that's not enough!
你已经在那做了十年 然后呢？
You've been there 10 years and what?
他说一句“够了 不用了”？
He's just gonna say, "That's it, no more"?
-嗯 -这就是他们要说的
- Mm-hmm. - That's exactly what they're gonna say.
而且他们能并且也这么做了
And they can and they did.
就是这样
And that's all.
我父亲十年都在为这些人工作
10 years my father's working for these people.
他得到了什么？什么也没有
And what has he got to show for it? Nothing.
没有退休金 没有养老保险
No retirement, no insurance.
知道吗 我真的很担心
You know what? I worry about that stuff, you know?
我们都很担心 孩子
Yeah well, we all worry about that, kid.
你准备怎么做？来吧 我们继续工作
What are you gonna do? Come on, let's get to work.
昨天你女儿生日开心吗？
Oh, your date was good?
我们去看了马戏表演 你准备怎么办？
It's the circus. What are you gonna do?
吉安娜很喜欢 那里有小丑 还有些别的
Giana loved it. There were clowns and things.
他们还有独角兽 和一些摇摇晃晃的东西
You know, they had a unicorn and some craziness.
-你知道吧？ -是吗？
- You know? - Oh yeah?
嘿 帝国到底是做什么生意？
Hey, so what's the deal at Empire?
有保险或者退休金之类的吗？
You know, far as insurance or retirement?
又是退休金的事？你担心退休金 还太早
Again with the retirement? You're too young to worry about retirement.
尤其是跟这些流氓共事 相信我
Especially with those hoodlums, believe me.
你老说这个 到底是什么交易？
Ahh, you keep saying that. What's the deal?
不正当交易 对吗？ 通常都在小房间里进行？
They're crooked, right? Huh, always in that room?
是 他们可不是在里面 玩纸牌游戏 伙计
Yeah. They ain't playing Tiddlywinks in there, pal.
你就在外面等 行吗？
You just wait out here, okay?
你就像卡通里的人一样 担心的事太多了
You're like that cartoon thing-- you worry too much.
[布朗克斯 合资格机构买家]
嘿 伙计们 你们好吗？
Hey, guys, how you doing?
相信我 你待在外面 会被叫干重活的
Trust me, from here out you'll be doing the heavy lifting,
我跟你保证 他们付的薪水可不够...
I guarantee you that. They don't pay me enough to do--
举起手来！
Get your hands up!
好 哇哇哇
It's okay, whoa whoa whoa.
闭上他妈的嘴！闭嘴！
Shut the fuck up! Shut up!
闭嘴！
Shut the fuck up!
快点 到这来 混蛋！
Come on, come here, you motherfucker!
-混蛋 混蛋！ -我会杀了你 不！
- Motherfucker, motherfucker! - I'll kill you, no!
去你妈的...
Get the fuck--
不不 嘿！
No no, hey!
不！
No!
嘿！
Yo yo, hey!
玛丽...
Marie...
快离开这 我们走！
Get the fuck outta here. Let's go!
该死的钱！
Fuck the money!
我们快离开这
Let's get the fuck outta here.
算那孩子走运 他穿了防弹背心
Kid's lucky he was wearing a vest.
不然 他就玩完了
If not, game over.
-毫无疑问 -那孩子叫波特米什么的
- No doubt. - The kid's named Potami or something.
他就在那
He's right over there.
我要过去跟他聊两句
I'm gonna go talk to him.
波特米先生
Mr. "Potami."
我是杰瑞罗森 警察...
I'm Jerry Ransone, cop...
就是侦探 你懂的
detective, you know.
他死了吗？
Is he dead?
是 很有可能
Yeah. High probability.
听着 波特米先生...
Listen, Mr. Potami--
嘿嘿 哇
hey hey. Whoa whoa.
放松点 好吗？
Easy,okay?
听着 如果你没别的事可做
Listen, if you had anything to do
不管你现在在做什么还是就此罢休吧 听我的没错
with this whole whatever-just- went-down-- listen to me,
早走比晚走好 如果 你想直接给我一枪
now's a better time than later if you want to shoot straight with me.
我会给你个机会
I'm giving you a chance.
听起来对你很公平？
Sound fair to you?
听着 我不是在浪费你的时间
Listen, I'm not gonna waste your time,
我也不想你浪费我的时间 我也有自己的生活
I don't want you to waste my time. I got a life too.
-我还有一堆破事要做 -我已经跟其他警察坦白了
- I got a lot of shit to do, okay? - I already told the other cops.
我跟这事没有半点关系
Okay? I had nothing to do with this.
他是个好人 我喜欢他 他有个美满的家庭
He's a good guy. I liked him. He had a family.
现在已经支离破碎 行了吗？
Fucking break already, okay?
没事 这孩子是清白的
It's all right. The kid's clean.
怎么？
What?
他是清白的 那孩子是清白的 让他走
He's clean. The kid's clean. Let him go.
好吧 我得走了 我妈就是让我
All right, I'm gonna go. My motherjust wanted me
顺道过来 确定你还活着
to stop by, make sure you were alive.
-你该留下 -我还活着
- You should stay. - I'm still here.
你还好吗？
You Okay?
是 我...你知道
Yeah, I-- you know.
肋骨什么的被伤到了
Feels like I got kicked in the ribs or something.
要不怎么是枪呢
Yeah, except it was a gun.
谢天谢地 还好有防弹衣
Yeah, thank God for that gun-protector thing.
好吧 我得走了
All right, I'm gonna go.
-不 别 -你不吃点东西吗？
- No, don't. - Don't you want to eat?
-坐下 吃点东西 -我得去上班了
- Sit down, eat something. - I've gotta go to work.
回头见 很高兴你没事 克里斯
I'll see you guys later. Glad you're okay, Chris.
-谢谢 南希 -晚安
- Thanks, Nance. - Good night.
-她是个好女孩 -是啊
- She's a good girl. - Yeah.
-非常好的姑娘 我喜欢 -就像喜欢我妹妹一样
- Very nice girl. I like her. - Like a sister that I like.
-闭嘴 -嘿
- Shut up. - Hey.
主要的是你大难不死 谢天谢地
The main thing is that you're safe, thank God.
-这就是重点 -你的同事呢？
- That's the main thing. - And your partner?
这份工作可以照顾家人吗？
The job will take care for his family?
-他们是那样说 -这也是他们将要做的 对吗？
- That's what they said. - Then that's what they'll do, right?
他们是这么说的
That's what they said.
很好
Good.
哦 嘿！
Oh hey!
他妈的 大难不死
Fucking-a, malaka.
我想你父亲是家里的支柱 对吗？
I thought your dad was the man of steel, right?
-嘴巴放干净点 -抱歉 别在意我的用语
- With the mouth. - Oh, I'm sorry. Excuse my language.
发生了什么？我是说 那场该死的爆炸？
What happened? I mean a fucking bomb?!
-他的朋友刚因此丧命 埃迪 -我知道 真逊
- His friend was just killed, Eddie. - I know, that sucks.
-你在开玩笑吗？我是说... -这一切本不该发生
- Are you kidding? I mean-- - None of this would have happened
要不是因为你抽大麻害他不能当警察
if it wasn't for that thing with you smoking pot and all that.
-在齐柏林飞艇（乐队）的演出上 -我明白
- In the Led Zeppelin show. - No, I know.
-克里斯现在已经是一名警察了 -我知道 我很遗憾
- Chris would be a police officer now. - I know, I feel terrible.
顺便说一下 你说错了 是黑色安息日的演出
Yeah, you're talking about Black Sabbath, by the way.
我宁愿我们看的是齐柏林
Trust me, I wish we saw Zeppelin.
怎么回事 老兄？
What the fuck happened, bro?
-哦 -我走了
- Oop. - I'm gonna go.
-你要去哪？ -我要去躺一会
- Where are you going? - I'm gonna go lay down or something.
去躺一会？为什么每个人都...
Going to lay down? Why would everybody--
每个人都在我出现的时候离开？
everybody leaves when I show up?
看什么频道呢？
Yo, what channel's cable?
一个笨贼企图抢劫一辆装甲运钞车
A botched attempt at an armored-car robbery
其中一人死亡 留下了一堆问题
left one man dead and a slew of questions,
炸弹在光天化日之下
as a pipe bomb was detonated in broad daylight
于曼哈顿的伦诺克斯大道125号 被引爆的
at 125th and Lennox Avenue in Manhattan.
警察正在调查 劫匪有两名嫌疑犯
Police are investigating the robbery as two suspects,
都带着面具 逃离了现场
both wearing masks, fled the scene
据描述 是开着一辆蓝色的卡车
in what's being described as a blue van.
[上锁！]
波特米！
Potamis!
-什么事？ -你将要在这里值夜班
- Yeah? - So you'll be working nights here now.
什么？为什么？
What? Why?
我们的人在街上
We give our guys on the streets guns
应该对向他们亮枪的人亮枪
to shoot people who show up with other guns.
我接托尼的班 行吗？
I had Tony's back, okay?
很好 所以你现在要值夜班
Great. So you'll be working nights now.
你可以走了
You can go.
他在那
There he is.
警探哈里
Dirty Harry-
他干这份工作不错
Yeah, good job with that.
你们晚上不把钱放进来吗？
Aren't you supposed to bring the money inside at night?
我不知道 我们没放吗？
I don't know, are we?
-我只是问问 -我们也是
- I'm just asking. - So are we.
钱在外面很安全
The money will be fine out there.
事实上 你眼睛盯着车看 我们就不会有事
Exactly. Just keep an eye on the monitors and we'll all be fine.
明白？
Got that?
很好
Good.
我们走
Let's go.
老板都不在乎 我们还在乎什么？
The bosses don't give a shit. Why should we?
就是 去他妈的 我家还有孩子要养
Exactly. Fuck that. I got kids at home.
那些混蛋就给了托尼的老婆 五千块
The fuckers are giving Tony's wife 5,000
而不是五万 知道他们偷了 相信我
instead of 50. I know they're stealing it, trust me.
-什么 那些业主？ -操 对 业主
- What, the owners are? - Fuck yeah, the owners.
每个人都在里面捣鬼 每个人
Everybody's up to shit in there. Everybody.
是啊 每个人除了你 伙计
Yeah, everyone except you, bro.
那地方就是个笑话
Yeah well, the place is a joke.
我们走对面 操... 我不想惹那些家伙
Oh, let's cross. Fucking-- I don't want to deal with those guys.
-我们走对面 -什么 你爸爸今天上班？
- Let's cross. - What, your father working today?
-不 他... -什么？
- No, he-- - What?
-他们把他辞了 -什么？
- They let him go. - What?
干了10年他妈的就把他辞了
After 10 years they fucking let him go.
-混蛋 -没错 没比这更混蛋的 操...
- Fucking assholes. - That's it, no more. Fucking--
想想那些坐在凯迪拉克里的混蛋 对吗？
Thinking they're big shits in their Cadillacs, right?
-去他妈的混蛋 -抱歉说什么？
- Fucking big shots. - Excuse me?
我只想说你们开除了为你们工作10年 这家伙的爸爸
I'm just saying you fire this guy's fucking father after 10 years?
抱歉 我不确定我听清楚了
Sorry, I'm not sure I'm hearing you right.
我想至少你可以更厚道一点
I think the least you could do is be a little loyal.
我们走
Let's go.
-我不知道你在说什么 -去你妈的混蛋
- I don't know what you're saying. - Fucking big shots
坐在他们的凯迪拉克里 一坨屎
in their Cadillacs, right? Big shit.
-我可是坐火车的 -混蛋
- I take the trains, yo. - Asshole.
你知道吗 你应该把你工作的地方 洗劫一空
You know what? You should rob that place where you work.
你说那地方没有保安 所以
You say the place ain't got no security, so.
你说的对 我应该
Yeah, you're right. I should.
没错 我是对的 你不觉得他们完全是在欺骗吗？
Yeah, I am right! What, you don't think they'll screw it over?
他们欺骗你的朋友 看看他的下场
They screwed your friend over. Look at him.
让他老婆守寡
Fucking widow.
想想吧 想想他的孩子 老兄
Think about that. Think about his kids, bro.
是 我应该洗劫那
Yeah, I should rob them.
没错 你应该
Yeah, you should.
我们得修理他们 对吗？
We'll fix them, right? Yeah.
操
Fuck.
该死
Shit.
我是克里斯 编号18249
This is Chris. Code 18249.
我是霍尼韦尔 那个门在那边 是开着的吗？
Yo, this is Honeywell. Got a reading the gate's open there?
我不知道 那个...
Yeah, I don't know. The--
灯没开 现在看起来好多了
the light was blinking, but it looks good now.
好 警察说我们有报警装置 我们可以打电话
All right. Cops say we get a signal, we've gotta call.
别担心 如果有问题就打电话
No worries. Call if there's a problem.
-好 -行了
- Okay. - All right.
好 老兄 就让我...
All right, bro, just let me--
-再给我看一次 -你声音小点
- show it to me one more time. - Just keep your fucking voice down.
-再让我看一次 -别那么大声 行吗？
- Let me see one more. - Cut the shit, all right?
天呐！而且他们不会知道？
Holy shit! And they won't know?
他们多数时候都没数
They don't even count it half the time.
上帝啊 天呐
Jesus, holy shit.
当门打开的时候 摄像机就找不到 那地方真是个笑话
The camera doesn't even see the door when it opens. The place is a joke.
-让我想不拿都不行 -操蛋 对吗？
Like I even want to fucking take it. - You know, fuck it, right?
你明白吗？你应该把我也弄进那地方去
Do you understand? You gotta get me a job at this place.
你知道我们有25万能干什么吗？
Do you know what I could do with $25,000?
我可以举办我的婚礼 买新车
I could pay for my fucking wedding, my fucking car.
闭上你的嘴 冷静点 好吗？
Shh, keep your fucking mouth down. Calm down, okay?
相信我 我这么做是有原因的
Trust me, I did this for a reason.
-是啊 就为了拿钱 -不 闭嘴
- Yeah, to take the money! - No, it's just fucked up,
因为他们对托尼家所做的 那家伙还有个老婆
what they did to Tony's family. The guy had a fucking wife,
-一个小女儿 -听着 我也感觉很遗憾
- a little girl. - Yeah listen, I feel terrible too,
但是你知道吗 我们现在 可以去搞个聚会吗？
but you know what? Can we go out and party already?
-好 去他妈的 -谢谢 上帝啊
- All right, yeah. Fuck it. - Thank you. Jesus.
-去找点乐子... -在我们走之前 我先去个地方
- Have a bit of fun every once-- - I gotta make one stop before we go.
嘿 我们走 注意你的眼睛...
Hey, let's go. Get your fucking eye--
-为什么？ -快他妈的走！
- Why? - Let's fucking go!
为什么 你留下了100块？
Why, you leaving $100?
你为什么停下
Why are you stopping?
我不想当混蛋 但是来真的？
I don't wanna be a dick, but really?
真的
Really.
-卡布丽缇夫人吗？ -是的
- Mrs. Cappolitti? - Yes.
我 呃...
I, uh--
我是托尼的好朋友
I was a good friend of Tony's.
我想把这个给你
I wanted to give this to you.
-抱歉？ -你就拿着吧
- Excuse me? - Please just take it.
我真的很遗憾
I'm really sorry.
我们 先走可以走了吗？
We, uh, good to go now?
是的 我们走
Yeah, let's do it.
好的！
All right!
在我梦里...
In my dreams...
这地方就是一滩臭水
This place reeks of Aqua Net.
啊
Ugh.
嘿 这边 我们的位置在这
Hey, right here. This is our spot right here.
-好 -我们要四杯卡米卡兹
- All right. - Can we get four kamikazes
再来一瓶你们这最贵的香槟 好吗？
and a bottle of your most expensive champagne, all right?
-再要一轮长岛冰茶 -我要白俄罗斯 埃迪
- And a round of Long Island ice teas. - I want a white Russian, Eddie.
-一杯白俄罗斯给这位漂亮的皇后 -今晚大家都应该感到扫兴
- A white Russian for the beauty queen. - Everyone should chill tonight.
-真扫兴 -照做就是！
- Just chill. - Just do it!
你们在哪弄来的这些钱？
And where the fuck did you get all this money?
-克里斯从有钱的地方偷的 -嗯？
- Chris stole it from the money place. - Hmm?
放松 老兄 大家都知道 我们只是些小喽
Relax, bro. Everybody knows I'm just fucking around.
拜托 谁会觉得你是从 上班的地方偷的？
Come on, who thinks you stole from where you work?
-该死 我要抽烟 -好
- Shit, I need smokes. - Right?
-我们去酒吧 -你们要去哪？
- Let's go to the bar. - Where are you going?
-我去买点香烟 -给我也买点 好吗？
- I'm going to get cigarettes. - Get me some, all right?
-去你妈的 埃迪 自己买 -你抽的都是我的烟
- Fuck you, Eddie, get your own. - You smoke all my cigarettes.
滚开
Fuck off.
当你有钱的时候 这地方 就是一坨屎 对吗？
Yo, this place is the shit when you got cash, right?
你真的该学着闭嘴 明白吗？
You know, you really gotta learn to keep your mouth shut, you know that?
-是很多很多钱 对吗？ -闭嘴 没错！
- It is a lot of cash though, right? - Fuck yeah, it is!
-很多很多钱 -闭嘴 没错
- A lot of fucking cash. - Fuck yeah, it is.
看看那是谁 老兄 迈克和吉米 瞧他们
Yo, look who it is, bro. Mike and Jimmy, look at them.
坐在该死的包厢里 他们以为 他们算哪根葱？
Yeah, big shots in the bullshit room thinking who they are, right?
-就是几个混到 -跟他们一起的人是谁？
- Couple of jerk-offs. - Who are they with?
从杰克逊高地来的波多黎各人 谢谢你 宝贝
Puerto Ricans from Jackson Heights. Thank you, sweetheart.
-我知道他们是谁 -波多黎各人？
- I know what that is, right? - Puerto Ricans, huh?
可乐 去看看那边在干嘛
Coke. Gonna say what's up.
你上哪去？
Yo, where are you going?
你要去哪？
Where are you going?
-这是VIP专区 -没错
- Yo, it's VIP only. - Yeah, exactly.
不管你们想怎样 跟我说 吉米
Whatever you guys need too, just talk to me, Jimmy.
-我们会好好伺候你 -喔！
- We'll take care of you. - Ho ho!
大混蛋 不错！
Big shit, nice!
你在这个房间可以看到全场
You can see the whole fucking room from this place.
-看 我看起克里斯了！ -你他妈的在这干嘛 埃迪？
- Look, I can see Chris! - What the fuck you doing here, Eddie?
我只是刚好在这 老兄 出来玩玩
What, I'm just here, bro. I'm just hanging out.
近来怎么样？ 你们这些家伙还好吗？
垄'.Qu茅 pasa, amigo? H掳W are YOU guys doing?
-好吗？ -我们在谈生意
- Okay? - We were discussing business,
-能麻烦你先离开吗？ -什么？
- uh, you know. So can you go, please? - Yeah yeah yeah, what?
什么？我不算生意人吗？
What? I'm not a businessman?
我看起来不像是可以自己 料理生意的人？
I don't look like I can conduct business myself?
怎么？我做的都是生意 老兄
What? I'm all business, bro.
那就是我 我来这聚会
That's what I am. I'm here to party.
你们这些家伙也是来聚会的吗 你知道我什么意思吗？
Are you guys here to party, you know what I mean?
我买了香槟 但你们却在喝可乐
I got the champagne, you guys got the coke.
来吧 我们做个交易 你想要我怎么做？
Come on, let's make a deal. What do you want me to do?
行吗？这些人就是你跟我说的 在餐馆里的人
Right? These are the guys you were telling me about at the diner.
-波多黎各人 对吗？ -哥伦比亚人
- The Puerto Ricans, right? - Colombians.
-谁？ -叙利亚人
- Who? - Syrians.
你他妈的怎么摊上这么个主？
You fucking have a funny guy here, huh?
谁 你说谁？
Who? What'd you say?
我说你在这搞笑吧？
I said you think you're the funny guy here, huh?
我...我是来搞笑的？
All my-- I'm the funny guy?
抱歉 老兄 我听不懂你说的话
I'm sorry, bro. I can't understand a fucking word you're saying.
天呐 你原来不会说人话
Holy shit. Yo, you actually talk like that?
-你认真的吗？ -埃迪 埃迪 过来
- Like for real? - Eddie, Eddie, come here.
-有没有人能告诉我这白痴是谁？ -闭嘴 过来
- Somebody tell me who this idiot is. - Shut up, come here.
-我喜欢这家伙 真有意思 -谢谢
- I like this funny guy. - Thank you.
埃迪 过来
Eddie! Come here.
-什么？ -过 来
- What? - C'mere, here.
-你可以待会帮我结账 -哦 得了吧！
- You can pay me later. - Oh, come on!
我不是那种... 你把我当什么人？
I'm not that kind of-- who do you think I am?
拜托 老兄 这家伙
Come on, bro. This guy.
他以为他妈的这样就可以打发我
He thinks he can fucking just pay me off.
-你们要喝香槟吗？ -快走
- You want the champagne? - Just go.
给你 好好享受吧 好吗？
Here. Enjoy that, guys, all right?
-谢谢 -不客气
- Thank you. - All right,
我要你们好好伺候这 你们明白我意思吧？
I'm gonna go take care of this. You know what I mean?
-我马上就回来 -是
- I'll be right back. - Yep.
该死的包厢 真贵 哇
Fucking room-- fancy shit, wow.
-那家伙就是个白痴 -智障
- The guy's an idiot, you know? - Retarded.
这些家伙什么时候变得这么有钱？
Since when do these jerk-offs have so much money?
我刚也在想这事
I was just thinking the same exact shit.
该死的混蛋
Chateau de Shit.
这混蛋有朝一朝得意 他会整晚都拿这说事
Asshole blows enough lines, he'll be talking all night.
没错
All right!
好像每个袋子里都有25万
There's like $25,000 in each bag.
而且每个袋子都锁在该死的门背后
And each bag is locked behind this fucking gate.
摄像机几乎看不到
The camera doesn't even look,
而且他是晚上整个地方的保安
and he's the only fucking security guy in the whole place at night.
啊 耶
Uh, yeah.
-你他妈的去哪了？ -克里斯
- Where the fuck were you? - Chris.
埃迪刚告诉了我们 关于25万的事
You know, Eddie was just telling us about the 25Gs.
晚上那只有你一个人 是真的吗？
That true you're the only guy there at night?
我们刚只是在聊天 老兄
We were just talking, bro.
你知道 我们只是好奇
Yeah, so, you know, I'm just curious,
你怎么...你怎么能偷这么多钱 而且他们什么都不知道？
you know, how can-- how can you take that much and they don't know nothing?
-嗯？ -告诉他们
- Hmm? - Tell them how they leave
卡车都是整晚带着钱留在外面
the truck outside overnight with the fucking money in it.
-够了 好吗 埃迪？ -他 告诉他们
- Enough, Eddie, okay? - Tell them that.
不管你们在打什么鬼主意 忘了这事
Whatever you guys are thinking, forget it.
伙计 他不知道他自己在说什么
Guys, he doesn't know what he's talking about.
-克里斯 只不过要简单的1 2 3条... -够了 好吗？够了
- Chris, it's-- it's a simple 1-2-3-- - Enough, okay? Enough.
埃迪 你为什么要跟那些人说？
Eddie, why would you say anything to those people?
你是不是脑子有问题 迈克...
I mean, it's like you're retarded. Mike--
他就是个疯子 你清楚
I mean, he's a maniac, you know that.
我们只是聊了几句 老兄 放松点
We were just talking, bro, relax.
你几乎都说出来了
You already said that.
除此之外 他们都是给斯皮罗工作的
Besides the fact, they work for Spiro!
去他妈的斯皮罗 他们根本不在乎斯皮罗
Fuck Spiro. They don't give a shit about Spiro,
没人在乎 你知道你没告诉我
nobody does. You know you didn't tell me
他们毫无理由的把卡车留在外面过夜
that they leave the truck outside overnight for no reason.
你知道我想采取行动 老兄
You know you wanted me to put it in action, bro.
谁想采取行动？你个白痴
Put what into action? Listen, you idiot,
脑子里都别打这些歪主意
get whatever stupid idea is in your head out of your head.
说正经的 我问你 会发生的 最糟的事 是什么？
Seriously, let me ask you, what's the worst that could happen, what?
乔吉当了偷车贼被判了多久 一年？
What did Georgie get that one time for auto theft, a year?
一年不值得让你尝试一百万？
And a year ain't worth a chance at a million dollars?
我们这跟偷车是两回事 埃迪
We're not talking about robbing a car, Eddie.
我不想余生都给做任人宰割的羔羊 老兄
I'm not cleaning lambjizz the rest of my life, bro.
我父亲在他42岁的时候就去世了
My father died when he was 42.
你父亲...我无意冒犯 但是他只是
Your father-- no offense, but he just got canned
-给斯皮罗清理厕所 -说话小心点
- for cleaning Spiro's toilets. - Watch your mouth.
好吧 对不起 听着
All right, I'm sorry. Look,
我说的就是你好好想想吧 好吗？
all I'm saying is think about it, okay?
你今晚回家的时候好好想想 好吗？
Just think about it when you go to your house tonight, okay?
最糟糕的结果就是 我会因为抢劫 运钞车而坐牢
Worst-case scenario, I go to jail for robbing a fucking truck,
你知道 坐一年
you know, for a year.
另外 我们都准备好了
Anything else, we're set.
我们准备好了
We're set.
好好想想吧
Fucking think about it.
我们准备好了 老兄
We're set, bro.
哈密尔顿博汉农 1978年
Hamilton Bohannon, 1978.
祝你今晚愉快 纽约
Have a great night, New York.
瞧瞧你 伙计
Look at you, buddy.
跟25万美金坐在那
Sitting in there with $25 million.
那可是一大笔钱
That's a lot of money.
好 埃迪 今晚 在餐厅
Okay, Eddie, the diner, tonight.
听着 克里斯 我得确保 这家伙会守口如瓶
Look, Chris, I just gotta know that this asshole can keep his mouth shut.
行吗？如果被斯皮罗知道 我和吉米
Okay? If Spiro finds out, we're dead,
-都死定了 -你不信任我？
- me and Jimmy. - Why, you don't trust me?
不！
No!
听着 别再废话了 好吗？
Listen, no more bullshitting, okay?
说正经的 迈克说的对
This is serious. And Mike's right.
只有天知地知 你知我知 好吗？
Nobody but us knows anything about anything, okay?
他怎么回事？
What's his problem?
我只是...我只是在想
I just-- I just think
如果我们要干这个 我们应该让斯皮罗也参与进来
if we're going to do this, we should let Spiro in on it, no?
如果你告诉斯皮罗 他会全吞了
You tell Spiro, he'll want it all.
是 但是我们不必全部都给他
Yeah, but we don't have to give it to him all.
我说的对吗？
See what I'm saying?
埃迪是对的
Eddie's right.
他是个白痴 不过他是对的
He's tr茅los, but he's right.
斯皮罗什么都不会知道
Spiro can't know nothing.
你觉得不会被他发现？
What, you don't think he's gonna find out?
不 我不觉得
No, I don't.
好
Okay.
好 吉米
Okay, Jimmy.
我是认真的 我们都是认真的
I'm serious. We're serious.
你有问题吗？
Are you good with that?
嘿
Hey.
他在问你话呢
He's asking you a question.
呃 我退出
Eh, I'm out.
-操 -你退出
- Fuck it. - You're out.
你不需要我 你已经有这俩家伙了
You don't need me for this. You got two guys anyway.
我这周末准备去电影院 搞建筑
I was going to do construction at the movie theater this weekend.
行了吗？我要走了
All right? I'm gonna go.
听着 我们还在做哥伦比亚的交易
Look, I'm still in for the Colombian deal.
对吗？不管它怎么跌价
All right? However that goes down,
但这...
but this...
不靠谱
it's-- no.
我要走了
No, I'm gonna go.
-你确定 -是
- You sure? - Yeah.
他妈的 那我就可以分更多钱 对吗？
Fuck him. More money for me then, right?
好吧
Okay.
别担心 好吗 克里斯？
Don't worry, all right, Chris?
别担心 他知道我会杀了他
Don't worry. He knows I'd kill him.
我们很好
We're good.
对
Right.
-好 -好
Okay okay.
好吧 这个...
Okay, this...
就是帝国
is Empire.
[帝国]
[帝国证券公司]
[帝国 纽约证券公司]
周四晚上 会只有我一个人在那
Okay, Thursday night I'll be the only one there.
埃迪 在波士顿路 那会有个栅栏
Eddie, off Boston Road there'll be a fence.
在栅栏顶端 有个摄像头
At the top of the fence, there'll be a camera.
我要你打碎它
I want you to break it.
第二天晚上 周五晚上...
The next night-- Friday night--
-保安8点就下班 -我们明天见
- the guards will be out by 8:00. - I'll see you tomorrow.
没人会加班 相信我 他们都是打卡上下班
Nobody gets overtime, so believe me, they'll be out like clockwork.
8点整
8:00 sharp.
两个街区外 在杰罗姆街 有个电话亭
There's a phone booth two blocks away on Jerome Avenue.
你和迈克去那等着
You and Mike will go there and you'll wait.
我再进去 确保一切顺利进行
I'll go inside, so I'll make sure everything's cool.
我说正经的 你就待在外面等
But I'm serious, you stay out there and you'll wait.
什么都别做 直到我打电话给你
And nothing happens until I call you.
什么都不做 直到我打电话
Nothing... until I call.
嘿 哇哇哇 嘿！
Hey, whoa whoa whoa, hey!
他没问题 没问题 没问题 还有其他人在这吗？
He's okay, he's okay, he's okay, he's okay. Anyone else here?
-还有其他人在这吗？ -什么？没有
- Is anyone here?! - What? No.
-好 -怎么回事？
- All right. - What's going on?
我们有组工作人员进来了 你知道吗？
We got a tip a crew's coming in here. You know anything about it?
-你知道点什么吗？ -不不
- Do you know anything about it? - No no.
好 到楼顶上去 楼梯在那边
All right, get up on the roof. Staircase's right there.
确保门的安全 检查周边
Secure that door. Check the perimeter.
大家 行动！
Everyone, move!
我们已经去了楼上 楼下 所有地方
I've been upstairs, downstairs, all over the place.
这里什么都没有
Nothing in here.
摄像机好像发生故障了
Camera look like it's out of order,
嘿 你准备怎么办？
but hey, what you gonna do, huh?
除了这些 就只有老鼠在忙了
Other than that, not a mice stirring.
你知道这地方有多少违规吗？
Do you have any idea how many violations are going on in this place?
-这太疯狂了 -是啊是啊
- It's crazy. - Yeah yeah,
这就像糖果店里的安保设备
it's about as secure as a candy shop.
-嘿 这只有钱 对吗？ -是的 的确
- Hey, it's only money, right? - Yeah, exactly.
好 我再进去检查最后一遍
All right, I'll take one last look around the premises.
-别抱怨 -当然
- Just holler. - For sure.
你介意我在这坐一会吗？
Mind if I do a few sets on your thing over there?
别客气
You know, knock yourself out.
都因为我家
'Cause it's Nautilus by the gym
边上健身房里的鹦鹉螺
over by my place.
你知道他们在说什么吗？
You know what they say?
静负载 这是
Dead weight, that's the only way
得知尺寸的唯一方法 明白吗？
to really get that size on, you know?
感觉这灼烧感了吗？
Gotta feel that burn.
-是啊 -这工作有点繁重
- Yeah. - Little hard work,
不要穿宽大的衬衫来
no big shirts.
你应该知道怎么做
You know how it is.
什么？
Yo?
那有警察 你知道吗？
The fucking cops are here, you hear me?
-你他妈的是在跟我开玩笑吗？ -该死的警察
- Are you fucking kidding me? - Fucking cops--
-他们已经在里面了 -嘿
- they're already inside and I fucking-- - Yo!
嘿嘿嘿 你在这干什么？
Hey hey hey, what was that there?
-什么？ -你在干什么？
- That? - Yeah, what was that?
我只是...
Naw, I was just, uh--
我只是在跟我妈妈打电话
you know, I was talking to my mother.
-是你妈妈吗？ -不是 她...
- That was your mother? - No, she was--
我不知道 她可能正在做饭吧
I don't know, she was doing some cooking or something.
-我想去一下厕所 可以吗？ -可以 就在那边
- I'm gonna go use the bathroom, okay? - Yeah, it's right down there.
你确信不再打给她？
You sure you don't want to call her back?
不了 没事
No no, that's okay.
就这样吧
That's what I'm talking about.
老板 我们在这没什么发现
I think we got something out here, boss.
收到 继续
Roger that. On the move.
撤 已经够了
Let's roll. Enough with the weights.
-撤退 -大家都离开这
- Everyone move! - Let's go. Move!
该死的
Fuck.
事情进展的怎么样了？ 快点 跟我说吧
How are things going out there? Come on, talk to me.
两个人 都有武器 还戴了面具
Two perps, both armed, masks on.
-一个从栅栏这逃了 -还有一个呢？
- One just slipped the fence. - Anyone else?
还没找到
Negative.
知道了
Roger that.
-你准备好了按摩？ -准备好了
- You ready? - Ready.
你留在这
You stay.
-你准备好了吗？ -准备好了
- You ready? - I'm ready.
好 那我们去吧
Let's do this.
不许动 不许动 放下武器
Freeze! I said freeze, drop your weapons!
该死的 快回来 蹲下来 蹲下来 不要动
Ah shit, get back. Stay down, stay down. Don't move.
强森 请求支援 请求支援
Johnson, call for backup. Call for backup.
这里发生了激烈的枪战
There's shots fired down here!
-我们需要支援 -罗尼 你看见什么了？
- We need backup! - What do you see, Ronny?
伙计 快跟我说
Talk to me, buddy. Talk to me.
那秃顶的男人藏在卡车后面
The bald perp's behind the trucks.
没露出眼睛 如果他们移动的话 我就能抓住他们
No eyes on him. If they move, I got 'em.
很好 有什么情况就继续 向我禀报 明白了吗？
Okay, you see anything, you talk to me, you got it?
收到
Roger that.
-强森 你到后面去 -知道了
- Johnson, get to the back. - Roger. I got it.
你就呆在这 不要动 明白吗？
Stay here, don't move. You hear?
-你要去... -不要动 呆在那
- What are you-- - Don't move, stay there!
罗尼 有什么发现吗？
Any visuals, Ronny?
还没有
Huh-uh, nothing yet.
快派人过来 这里发生了激烈的枪战
Dispatch, we've got guns fired here.
我们在帝国需要支援 这里的情形不怎么好
We're gonna need backup at Empire. Situation just got real.
10-71 杰罗姆大街2号
10-71, code two Jerome Avenue.
-是的 -我们需要支援 我们需要支援
- Yeah. - We need backup! We need backup here!
集中注意力在一个人身上
Got eyes on one.
就在门边 门边
By the gate, by the gate!
先生 没打中 还有一个躲在卡车后面
No hits, sir. One's still behind the truck.
知道了 坚持下去
Roger. Stay the course.
有两辆车朝这开过来了
Two cars headed over. On their way.
知道了
Roger that.
我们这的情况不怎么好
We've got a real situation here.
汤米 你那边怎么样？
Tommy, what's your 10-39?
正要进入杰罗姆大街了 再坚持一下
Turning onto Jerome Avenue now. Hold tight.
老板 请问我们要怎么做
Talk to me, boss. What do you need?
你需要我们做什么 请回答
What do you need? Talk to me, what do you need?
还是没找到那个人
Still no visual on the perp, sir.
还是没找到
Still no visual.
老板 我没听见你的回答
Boss, I'm getting no response here.
躲在卡车后面的那个人也不见了
Lost eyes on the one behind the truck, sir.
他是全副武装
He's definitely armed.
罗尼 你那边怎么样了？
Ronny, talk to me. Do you have eyes on the situation?
支援 我们这需要支援
Backup, we're gonna need some backup here!
有人回答我吗
Somebody's gotta give me something out there.
请回答 请回答
Talk to me! Talk to me!
老板 你需要我们做什么？
What do you need me to do, boss?
开火了 开火了
Shots fired, shots fired.
支援 我们这需要支援
Backup, we need backup, we need backup!
他们开火了 开火了
Shots fired, shots fired!
我们需要支援
Shots fired, we need backup!
我们需要支援 这里都应付不过来了
We need backup! We've got officers engaged in gunfire here.
你大概什么时候到？
What's the ETA?
现在正在进入帝国
Coming into Empire now.
老板 你那边情形怎样？
Boss, what's the situation out there?
-有车朝这里开过来了 -解除警报 解除警报
- We've got cars arriving. - All clear, everything's all clear.
10-26号解除警报
10-26 all clear.
支援人员刚刚到达现场
Backup arriving on the scene right now.
知道了
Roger that.
快躲开
Move!
这他妈的是怎么回事？
What the fuck was that about?
你他妈的闭上你的大嘴巴
It's about somebody with a big fucking mouth I'm gonna have to shut.
-在那 -可能只是巧合
- F-- there he is. - It could have been a coincidence.
埃迪 这只是不可能是巧合
Ain't no such thing as a coincidence, Eddie.
迈克 你他妈的在这里干嘛
Mike, what the fuck you doing here?
-吉米 怎么了？ -迈克 等一下
- What's up, Jimmy? - Mike, wait--
你他妈的是要背叛我吗？
Want to rat me out, you fucking scumbag?
-迈克 我没有 -他妈的就是你做的
- Mike, I didn't-- - Fucking do it.
给我起来 在帝国我们
Get up. We ain't calling quits
就不在同一位子 明白吗？ 他妈的给我进来
on that Empire place neither, okay? Get the fuck in!
是啊 他杀死了一个人 他是英雄
Yeah, he shot the guy. He's a hero.
他救了警察 那样他就不用死了
He saved the cop's life. He could've died.
我的儿子 我的儿子
MY 5掳", my son...
他在那 来了
There he is, there he is!
我的英雄
My hero.
来打个招呼
- Say hello.
我跟埃迪说几句话
I'm gonna go talk to Eddie for a minute.
-埃迪 -我马上就回来
- Eddie. - I'll come back, I'll come back.
好吧 他现在是英雄了 就没时间陪妈妈了
Oh, now he's a hero he has no time for his mother.
你去哪了？一早上我都在打你电话
Where you been? I was calling you all morning.
我在哪？你他妈的在哪？
Where was I? Where the fuck were you?
你知道昨晚多疯狂吗？
How crazy was that shit last night?
还有别人跟我们做一样的事
Another crew comes to do the same fucking shit?
你怎么了？你去哪了？
What? What's up with you? Where were you?
迈克昨晚把吉米杀了
Well, Mike killed Jimmy last night.
我当时就在现场
That's where I was.
-什么 -是的
- What? - Yeah.
他认为他背叛了我们 现在他想进去再抢一次
Thought he ratted us out, now he wants to go back in and rob Empire again.
-什么 你们他妈的疯了吗？ -不是我 是他
- What, are you fucking crazy? - It's not me, it's him!
吉米跟我们昨晚做的事就设关系 明白吗？
Jimmy had nothing to do with what went down last night, okay?
-那他妈的只是巧合 -我知道 可有什么办法
- It was a fucking coincidence. - I know. You know what?
太晚了 他已经被杀死了
It's too late. Killed him, so.
斯皮罗发现这事后会怎么做？
What the fuck's Spiro gonna do when he finds out about this?
他会杀了我们的 明白吗？
You know he's gonna fucking kill us, right?
所以我说我们再进去
That's why I say we gotta go back in there
然后在迈克之前把钱拿出来
and take the money for ourselves before Mike,
-要比他 比任何一个人都快 -什么？
- before him, before anybody else does. - What?
你他妈的也疯了吗？
Are you fucking crazy?
-没有 -他们不会再把钱
- No. - They're not gonna leave the money
-放在大街上了 明白吗？ -所以我们进里面去拿
- on the street any more anyway, okay? - So we go inside and get it!
你他妈的忘了这事 忘了它
Just fucking forget it. Forget everything.
门上有摄像机 明白吗？
There's cameras at every door, okay?
我怎么可以说呢？ 我怎么可以...
So why am I even talking? I'm not even-- I'm not--
警察不会想到的 没人想的到
Cops won't expect it. Nobody will.
闭嘴 你他妈的能闭嘴吗？
Shut your fucking mouth. Will you please shut your fucking mouth?
-有没有你我都会去做的 -真的吗？
- I'm doing it with or without you. - Oh really?
-你不和我一起干？ -是的
- You gonna do it without me? - Yeah yeah, really.
我到那后 你可以打电话给警察 你他妈的甚至可以朝我开枪
And when I get there, you can call the cops, you can fucking shoot me
或许你就说 埃迪 我和你一起 明白吗？
or you can say "Fuck yeah, Eddie, I'm with you." But you know what?
反正我会做的
I'm doing it.
做完这事后我就再也不做了 但这事我一定会做
And I'm not doing this shit any more, bro. I'm fucking done with this.
-我会做 -闭嘴 好吗？
- I'm done. - Watch your mouth, okay?
你自己小心
You watch it.
克里斯 我会做的
I'm doing it, Chris.
就在今晚八点
I know it's just you after 8:00.
现在我要跟纽约说再见 然后出发去阳光充足的加利福尼亚
...And it was sayonara New York for sunny California.
1972年的南加州从不下雨
Albert Hammond in 1972.
我现在在一架波音747上
Got on board a westbound 747
我做梦都没想过会这样
Didn't think before...
我要做什么呢
What to do
喔 人生充满机遇
Oooh, that talk of opportunities
荧屏电影上的一切
TV breaks and movies
就要成为现实
Rang true
Sure rang true...
他是疯了 对吧？
He's fucking crazy, right?
克里斯 你应该知道的
You know that Chris
疯了 我他妈的真是疯了
Fucking crazy, I'm always fucking crazy.
你知道我在这 对吧？
Well, here I am, right?
-你知道他妈的有多少次... -该死的埃迪
- You know how many fucking times-- - Fucking Eddie.
不可置信吧 可我他妈的就是来了
Fucking unbelievable. Say I'm fucking coming, right?
我会弄开它的
Totally won't split it.
那个怎么样？
How about that?
他妈的就没人相信我 是吗？
Nobody around wants to fucking believe me, right?
操你妈的什么东西？
What the fuck?
我都跟你说了我会来 对吧？
I told you I was coming, right? Yeah.
就没人相信我 是吗？
No one ever wants to believe me, right?
可我已经来了 哇哦
Well, here I am, boys. Whoo!
哇哦
Whoo yeah!
-他妈的是什么东西？ -哇哦
- What the fuck? - Whoa!
你他妈的疯了？
What, are you fucking crazy?!
好吧
Well...
我都跟你说了我会来
I told you I was fucking coming, bro.
你觉得怎么样？
How about that?
我跟你说了 不是吗？
What'd I tell you, right?
我说过了
I told you.
钱在哪 嗯？
Where's it at, huh?
没拿到钱我是不会离开的
I ain't leaving without it.
兄弟 除非我拿到钱 否则我不会离开
Brother, I'm not leaving till I get that money.
没拿到钱我不会离开 明白吗？
I ain't leaving without it, okay?
看看你 你就像个疯子
Look at you, you look like a lunatic!
对 你说的对
Yeah, that's right, yeah.
快接电话 快点
Answer the phone, go ahead.
你快接电话
Answer the-- you answer the phone right now!
你难道现在就想朝我开抢吗？
You might as well shoot me dead right now, okay?
我不要进监狱 不要
I'm not going to jail. I'm not going to jail, bro!
-我不要再这样卑贱的生活 -闭嘴 你他妈的闭嘴
- I am not going to my shitty life-- - Shut up, shut the fuck up!
-闭嘴 -我不要进监狱
- Shut up! - I'm not going to jail.
-闭嘴 闭嘴 -我他妈的不要进监狱
- Shut up, shut up. - I'm not going to fucking jail.
我不要再过那样卑贱的生活
I'm not going back to my shitty life right now!
-快接电话 快点 -闭嘴 你闭嘴
- Answer the phone, go ahead. - Shut your mouth. Shut it.
是 我是18249号的克里斯
Yeah, this is Chris. 18249.
这里是霍尼韦尔公司 发生什么事了？
Hey, it's Honeywell. What's going on over there?
是发生什么骚乱了吗？
We got a reading. There's some kind of a disturbance or what?
你害死我了
You fucked me.
我们现在就能做了
We can fucking do this right now. We can fucking do this.
嘿 你在那里吗？
Hey, are you out there or what?
我这电话打扰你了吗？
Yo, you want me to call this in?
-克里斯 克里斯？ -达菲 没事
- Chris, Chris? - Yeah, it's okay, Duffy.
是我的灯掉了 这里一切正常
My-- my lights on here. Everything's fine.
-该死的 -那就好 你继续睡觉吧
- Fuck! - All right, go back to sleep.
-我不会再打扰你了 -嗯 没事
- I'll try not to wake you up again. - Yeah, okay.
快把这打开 我知道你有钥匙
Open this. Come on, I know you've got the keys.
快打开 钥匙在哪？
Open this right now. Where's the key right now?
快把钥匙给我
Give me the key, come on.
克里斯 把钥匙给我
Chris, gimme the key!
-我他妈的在干什么 -快打开
- What the fuck am I doing? - Open it.
-快打开 快点 -知道了 知道了
- Open it, open it. - Yeah. Yeah.
该死的
Fuck.
这个怎么打开？快打开
How do you open this? Open this right now.
你怎么打开？快打开
How do you open it? Open it.
快点！
Come on, open it!
快给我打开
真他妈的让人难以相信
Un-fucking-believable.
-真他妈的让人难以相信 -哦 天呐
- Un-fucking-believable. - Holy shit.
你他妈的把面具戴上
Put your fucking mask on.
我他妈的这是在做什么
What the fuck am I doing?
真该死
Fuck shit!
该死的 这是什么？
What the fuck?
你他妈的把狗杀了？
You shot the fucking dog?
是啊 谢谢你告诉我这有狗啊 可恶
Yeah, thanks for telling me there was a dog, asshole!
-该死的 -混蛋
- Fuck. - Dick!
真他妈难以相信
Un-fucking-real.
我他妈的要怎么和别人说 嗯？
What am I gonna fucking tell people, huh?
你就不能帮我提一下这个吗？
You gonna help me carry this shit out or what?
蠢蛋 那里有摄像头
There's a fucking camera, you idiot!
哪里？
Where?
你要做什么？ 还真他妈好啊 埃迪
Oh, what are you doing? That's fucking great, Eddie.
你让我怎么跟别人说 嗯？
What am I gonna tell people, huh?
你说啊 我要怎么跟别人说？
You tell me, what am I gonna fucking tell people now?
你被拍下来了 而且还跟我说话 你这蠢蛋
You're on the camera and you're talking to me, you fucking idiot!
Ｏ
ＯＣ
ＯＣＲ
ＯＣＲＳＵＢ
ＯＣＲＳＵＢ制
ＯＣＲＳＵＢ制 作
ＯＣＲＳＵＢ制 作 ｍｉ
ＯＣＲＳＵＢ制 作 ｍｉａｎ
ＯＣＲＳＵＢ制 作 ｍｉａｎｋｏ
ＯＣＲＳＵＢ制 作 ｍｉａｎｋｏｎｇ
可恶 现在我们都成小丑了
Damn, we got clowns in every room here.
该死的
Aww shit.
嘿 你能不能在联邦调查局
Hey, you might want to go holler at your boy there
来之前从这里离开
before these FBI clowns take over from him.
你和你的同事们还真是混乱啊
Looks like your party got a little out of whack here.
看看这地方
Look at this place, huh?
天呐 再看看你
God, look at you.
我当时正在打电话
Yeah, I, uh-- I was on the phone
-然后... -你在打电话？
- and then-- - You were on the phone?
你在那打电话？
You were on that phone right there?
-打电话给那边？ -不是 不是
- You make a call there? - No no.
-我... -不是什么
- I, uh... - Not that.
我不知道 我现在一片混乱
I don't know. My head's all messed up.
一个月三次 还真是疯狂啊
Three times in a month is crazy.
是啊 怎么会有这种可能性呢？
Man, what are the odds of that, huh?
三次 那些家伙
Three times. What are the odds
怎么就知道钥匙在哪 嗯？
that the guy knew exactly where the keys were too, huh?
令人难以置信啊
Unbelievable.
这狗竟然也因为害怕而晕倒了
The dog passed out from fear.
那该死的人吓坏了它
9mm must have scared the shit out of him.
他们看它没知觉了 还以为它死了
They found it unconscious. They thought it was dead.
他们以为这狗死了
They thought the dog was dead.
-我是罗森侦探 -我知道你是谁
- I'm Detective Ransone. - Yeah, I know who you are.
那在这发现什么情况了吗？
Listen, so what have we got here?
这个月这里已经被人三次闯入了
We've got three break-ins on the same premises,
死了两个人 没抓到人
we've got two men dead, we've got no arrests.
这里有人知道
Does anybody here have any idea how many
多少钱消失了吗？
dollars that disappeared from this spot?
罗森侦探
Uh, Detective Ransone
或这位先生...
or Mister-- how do you pronounce it?
是帕特觅吗？
--Patemi, is it?
是波特米提斯
Potamitis.
是嘛 你们知道
Yeah. See, now you know why
为什么联邦调查局来这了吗？
the FBI is rolling up in here.
所以
Yeah, so.
波特米提斯先生 是像圣诞老人
Mr. Potamias, you got Santa Claus
一样的人从天花板上掉下来 是吗？
coming through your ceiling, right?
他们破门而入
They break in your gate,
以非常近的距离向狗开枪
shooting a 9mm within proximity of your dog
而你却没察觉到
and you're unconscious.
不 我...
Yeah. No, I, uh...
我不知道 我当时正在巡视 回来后
I don't know. I was making the rounds. I come back
我想应该是有人袭击了我
and I guess somebody hit me.
你不是在打电话吗？
You weren't on the phone?
不是打电话吗？ 可你刚才跟我说你在打电话？
No phonecall? Didn't you tell me you were on that phone?
霍尼韦尔公司打电话过来 然后你说一切正常
Honeywell called and you said everything was okay.
-是一切正常吗？ -就像我说的
- Was it okay? - Yeah, like I said--
我在巡视 回来后
no, I was making the rounds. I come back and some--
有人袭击了你
Somebody hit you.
是的
Yeah.
你就没看见什么？
Nothing caught your eye?
当时就没什么不正常？
Nothing seemed out of the ordinary at that time?
外面的摄像头坏了
The camera outside's broke,
所以我能看见的就是这房间的门
so the only visuals I had were on the money room and the doors.
是啊 然后有人从天花板上掉了下来
Yeah, and somebody's coming through your ceiling.
还真是一部精彩的电影啊
That's a brilliant move. Whew.
-很聪明 -真的是很聪明
- Very clever. - It's really clever.
很聪明 很狡猾
Very clever, very tricky.
这些家伙不是人
Wow, these guys are something else, huh?
-先生 我没听懂 -你还有别的什么要说的吗？
- Excuse me, sir. - So you got anything else for us,
-这位... -帕特觅先生
- Mister... - Potami.
帕特觅先生？
Potami?
罗森侦探 你还有什么要问的吗？
Detective Ransone, any more questions?
不 你们已经问完了
No, I think you guys covered everything.
没有？很好 也就是说 我们在这的工作完成了 对吧？
No? Good. So we're done here, right?
哪个人把他送医院去吧
Somebody get this kid to a hospital.
-真是难以置信啊 -嗯哼
- Unbelievable. - Mmm.
波特米提斯先生 我是欧尼阿拉托斯
Mr. Potamatis, Ernie Anastos.
据说昨晚有九百万
It's been reported that over $9 million were taken
被抢劫了 你有什么要说的吗？
in last night's heist. Do you have anything to say about that?
没有
No.
我能问你些问题吗？
Can I just ask you a couple of questions?
就五分钟？
Five minutes?
继续拍 继续拍
Keep shooting. Keep shooting.
该死的埃迪
God damn it, Eddie.
嘿 嘿
Hey hey-
-嘿 -发生什么事了？
- Hey. - What's going on?
没什么 我... 我只是想去散步
Nothing, I was-- I need to go for a walk.
散步？你要去哪散步 嗯？
Go for a walk? Where are you gonna go for a walk, huh?
嗯？你要去哪散步？
Hmm? Where are you gonna go?
不是 我只是想去散步
Nowhere. I'm just going for a walk.
你要去哪里？ 警察可都在外面找你
Where you gonna go? The police are out there looking for you.
-你脑子没问题吧？ -好吧 我很抱歉
- You okay? - Yeah, I'm sorry.
-我...我很抱歉 -到底发生什么事了？
- I just-- I'm sorry. - What's going on?
-我只是想去散步 -发生什么事了？到底发生什么了？
- I gotta go for a walk. - What's going on? What's going on?
-没什么 我很好 -可你看起来不好
- Nothing. I'm fine. - You're not fine.
你看起来不好 说吧
You're not fine. Come on.
你一整夜都出去 可外面的警察也整天都在找你
You were out all night. The police are here all day looking for you.
你的脸...告诉我发生什么了吧
Your face-- come on, tell me.
说吧
Tell me, tell me.
-跟我说话 -没什么 我...
- Talk to me. - Nothing. No, I--
-我要去散步 -不行
- I'm gonna go for a walk. - No.
-我会回来的 我很好 -你看起来不好 听着
- I'm gonna come back. I'm okay. - You're not okay. Listen--
-你看起来很不好 -我很好 爸 我没事
- You're not okay. - I'm okay, Pop. I'm all right.
不要出去 克里斯 我在跟你说话 你听我的就对了
Don't walk away! Listen to me. I'm talking to you. Chris!
-克里斯 听我的吧 -我很抱歉
- Chris, listen to me! - I'm sorry.
如果因为那该死的埃迪
If goddamn Eddie has something to do with this
你再被警察抓了的话 我会杀了他的 明白吗？
to make the police come for you again, I'm gonna kill him, you hear me?
听见我说的话了吗
Listen to me!
我是美国地方检察官朱利尼亚 欢迎你来
U.S. District Attorney Giuliani, welcome.
-这是我的助手纽金特马里查 -嘿 你们好吗？
- Agents Nugent, Marichal. - Hey, how you doing?
-非常欢迎你来 -很高兴见到你们
- Hot enough for you or what? - Good to see you.
伙计 进展的怎么样？
How are you doing, fellas?
被抢了多少钱？
So how much are we talking about being taken here?
虽然报纸上说的不怎么详细
Yeah well, the newspapers are downplaying it,
但我们认为应该超过1干万元
but we think it's upwards of $10 million.
-天呐 -史上最大数额的案件了
- Jesus Christ. - The largest one in history.
难道那里只有一个保安吗？
And the security guard, there was only one?
只有一个 而且他好像根本就
Only one guard, but he doesn't really seem that capable
-不能胜任那个工作 先生 -怎么看起来好像
- of much of anything, sir. - Well, seemed capable of shooting
根据这个报道 两天内就能抓到抢劫犯啊
a would-be robber two nights prior according to this report here.
不错 但是听着
You're right about that, sir, but listen,
我们都觉得那只是个诱饵
we think that whole thing might have been a decoy.
因为我们现在已经监视了那人
Because we've got the guy on surveillance tape, right?
两天前 他在后面架了个摄像机
Two nights prior, he's disabling a video camera in the back.
所以你觉得这有什么联系？
So you think the two are connected?
是啊 这个细节 那个人
Yeah, but talking about details, manpower--
很有可能会这样做的
there's no doubt about it--
感觉好像我们在谈论科萨诺斯特拉 （黑手党 美国的一个秘密犯罪组织）
we're talking Cosa Nostra.
而一开始就参与进来的侦探...
And the detective who's been on since the beginning--
J.罗森侦探？
Detective J. Ransone?
是啊 他现在刚好
Yeah, he's setting up a makeshift interrogation
在帝国那时有临时审讯
over at Empire right now.
-很好笑吗？ -朱利尼亚先生 那个
- You find that funny? - Mr. Giuliani, there's no way in hell
外国佬肯定不能独自完成这件事的
that that greaseball guard could pull off this job on his own.
对他来说这事太难了 其实我很乐意去帮他的
It's just too big for him. I'm willing to put my badge on it.
让他去工作没什么坏处
Well, no harm in letting him follow through with the workers,
但我还是同意马里查的看法
but I tend to agree with Marichal here.
这是次集团犯罪
This thing stinks of organized crime.
-不错 -继续走访那五家人
- Agreed. - Go after all five families.
总有人会说的
Someone's gonna talk.
在检察官鲁道夫朱利尼亚的部署下
Under District Attorney Rudolph Giuliani's orders
五个犯罪家庭的成员
members of all five of New York's crime families
都被捕以审讯 关于帝国抢劫案的细节
have been arrested to be questioned in regard to the Empire heist.
你他妈的嘴唇上还留了东西
You missed some shit on your upper lip.
-你应该弄干净来的 -这案子被认为是
- You should shave that off. - Now believed to be the largest
自德国汉莎航空公司抢劫案 之后最大的案子
since Lufthansa.
战争...
War...
-八百万 九百万 到底多少钱 -嘿 你怎么样？
- $8 million, 9 million, how much is it? - Hey, how you doing?
-好像没人知道什么事 -嘿 后退
- No one seems to know anything... - Hey, back off!
-除了那次案件 -朱塞佩 钱在哪？
- ...Other than this is... - Where's the money, Giuseppe?
这就是美国历史上最大的抢劫案了
...The biggest heist in U.S. history.
女士们先生们 某个地方的人可是有一大笔钱的
Ladies and gentlemen, someone out there has a lot of cash.
这就是你的一半 一分不少
It's your half right there, every penny.
-我就说了可以成功吧 -操你妈的蠢蛋
- Told you we could pull that off. - You fucking ass!
他妈的我的脸都被毁了
That's for breaking my fucking face.
你怎么可以说
How else were you gonna say you had
你跟这事没一点关系 嗯？ 操你妈的
nothing to do with it, huh? Fuck!
我跟迈克说了 他想
I talked to Mike. He wants to, uh--
他想见我们
Mike wants to meet with us.
操你妈的
You fucking--
我能怎么办？是他打电话给我的
What was I supposed to do? He called me.
他说我们可以用 哥伦比亚人的方式跟他交易
He said we go in with the Colombian deal on him and that's it.
而且他不会跟任何人说的
He won't say nothing to anybody, so that's it.
-就这样 -我要进去了
- There it is. - I'm gonna get in my car.
你再出现在我面前的话 我他妈的就杀了你
You come around me again, and I'm gonna fucking kill you.
-我还能说什么？ -我他妈的要杀了你
- What else was I supposed to say? - I will fucking kill you.
-听明白了吗？ -我他妈的刚给你了八百万
- You understand me? - I just handed you $8 fucking million!
他妈的不是你给我的 明白了吗？
You didn't hand me fucking shit, you understand me?
-把你那该死的... -他妈的不要用手这样指我
- Get the fuck-- - Didn't hand me fucking shit.
他妈的给我走开
And you walk the fuck away
还有迈克也是 要不然我把你们俩都杀了
and you tell Mike to do the same or I'll kill you both.
-我他妈的会杀了你 -是啊 操你妈的
- I'll fucking kill you. - Yeah, fuck you!
他妈的当你出现在那的时候 我就该杀了你
I should have shot you when you came through that fucking roof.
操你妈的鸡巴
Fucking prick.
该死的可卡因
This fucking cocaine.
你知道我想杀了你吗？
You know I should kill you, right?
想把你的喉咙撕裂
Slit your throat...
就算当初 你对我做的那些卑鄙的事一样
for backstabbing me like you did.
这也是我现在来这的原因
I mean, that's why I'm here right now.
我会补偿你的
I'll pay you back.
那你朋友呢？
And your friend?
他不会 他只是...
He had nothing to do with it. He just...
还没背叛我而已
didn't rat me out, so.
就这样
That's it.
埃迪 我不是笨蛋
I'm not an asshole, Eddie.
你他妈的看着我 行吗？
Fucking look at me, okay?
听着 我参与了
Listen, I'm in.
我一直都参与了
I'm all the way in, so.
但是克里斯却想置身事外 所以就成这样了
But Chris stays out of it and that's the way it's gonna be.
你可以杀了我 你想怎么报复我都可以
You could shoot me, you could do whatever you want to do,
但是你知道吗？
but you know what?
杀了我的话 你也不知道钱在哪
Kill me, you don't find out where the money is, and...
而且我还会跟斯皮罗 说关于吉米的事
you know, and I'll tell Spiro about Jimmy, so.
你理解吗？
You know?
好吧
Okay.
那就推到明天解决
It goes down tomorrow then.
很好
Good.
千万不要给我玩失踪
Don't disappear.
-那里都不去 -嗯 那就好
- Not going anywhere. - Yeah.
很好 那现在给我滚出去
Good. Now get the fuck out.
好吧
All right.
-你有什么发现吗 -或许就在某个地方
- You got something? - Somewhere in here.
找到了
Got it.
-我们出去吧 -什么 出去？
- Let's get outta here. - What, we stepping out?
-是的 -好吧
- Yeah. - Okay, let's do this.
迈克尔 哪里是...
Michael, where's, um...
-什么？ -吉米在哪里？
- Where's what? - Where's Jimmy?
他最近去哪了？
Where's he been lately?
-吉米在工作 -我知道 我的意思是他没有
- Jimmy's working. - No, I know, he hasn't been here in--
他都快一星期没来这了
it's been like almost a week.
他可是一直都跟你在一起的 所以我很好奇
He's always with you. I'm just wondering.
我很好奇他在哪里
I'm just wondering where he is.
他现在在工地上
I think he's got the-- the construction thing.
-哦 是嘛 -他在电影院工作
- Oh yeah yeah. - He's been working at that movie house.
-嗯哼 -所以会有点忙
- Mm-hmm. - So it's been real busy over there.
雅尼 那看起来不错 你能打开吗？打不开吗？
Yanni, that looks good. Can you turn it on? You can't turn it on?
背景里的好像是火山
There's a lava in the back I think.
看起来还不错
It looks good anyway.
你要去哪里？
Where the hell are you going?
卫生间
Use the bathroom.
[外语]
嘿 我在找...
Hey, I'm looking for a...
斯皮罗斯查基斯
Spiro Stravakis.
-斯查基斯？ -是 斯查基斯
- Stavrakis. - Stavrakis!
哦 是警察吗？
That's good. Are the police asking?
-有这么明显吗？ -只有警察会来
- What, that obvious? - Only if you're the police.
是的 我们是来询问关于帝国抢劫案的
Yeah, we came here about the Empire heist.
我想知道有没有人知道什么信息
Just curious if anybody knew anything about it.
是布朗克斯区的帝国抢劫案吗？
The Empire heist in the Bronx?
-是的 -你们到这来找？
- Mm-hmm. - And you're here looking?
报纸上不是说是马夫做的吗
I thought the papers said that was the Guineas.
-他们可是一群暴民 -在我认为
- You know, the real mob. - Ah, you know.
不管是一流的下层阶级 还是三流的下层阶级
Big-time lowlifes, small-time lowlifes--
对我来说都是一样的
it's all the same to me.
在那的是迈克尔...
Ain't that right there, Michael...
迪米奇 我说的没错吧？
Dimitriu? Did I say that right?
你到我的地盘 还能叫出我们的名字
You come into my place and you start saying people's names,
-可你却没说自己的名字 -是啊
- but you never said your name. - You're right.
-我们没有说 -你这是在暗示什么？
- We didn't. - And what are you insinuating?
你是说迈克尔跟这抢劫案有关系吗？
That maybe Michael here had something to do with this robbery?
我只是想问问他们 知不知道点什么 就这样
Just want to ask your boy if he have any ideas on it, that's all.
伙计们 这侦探他妈的自我感觉
My boy, detectives, has the good fucking sense to know
如果我身边的人跟那事有什么关系
that if he or anyone around me had anything to do with something like this
他可以不经过我的同意就抓人
without my knowledge, that they'd lose their balls.
所以现在可以确信他根本 就是在捕风捉影
So no, you can be certain he has no ideas on this.
你是在替他回答吗？
So you're answering for him?
-我已经说过了 -他替你回答了
- I just did. - He's answering for you.
好吧 我们没找到什么线索
Okay. Well, we got nothing else.
-那再见？ -再见
- Yassou? - Yassou, yeah.
好吧
All right.
再见
Yassou.
迈克尔 坐
Michael, have a seat.
看 他在跟某个人说话
Look at him, he's talking to someone.
-婊子养的混蛋 -你确信？
- Son of a bitch. - You sure?
我相信他肯定看到摄像机了
I'm positive. He's looking right at the camera.
我一下午可就是在找它
I've been looking at this thing all afternoon.
啊 他来了
Ah, here he is.
婊子养的混蛋
Son of a bitch.
-嘿 克里斯 -嘿
Hey, Chris. Hey, man.
-嘿 -你怎么样？
- Hey. - How you doing?
进来吧 嘿 伙计们 让我单独跟他说话
Come on in. Hey, guys, give me the office for a sec.
-知道了 -我还没机会
- Sure. - Hey, listen, I never got the chance
说声谢谢呢 因为你救了我的命
to properly thank you for saving my life out there.
谢谢你
So thank you.
没事 看到你没事我就放心了
Yeah, I'm glad to see you're doing okay.
是啊 我也是 你......
Yeah, me too. Here, grab a--
随便找张椅子坐下吧
grab a seat, sit down.
你能来 我很感谢
Listen, uh, thanks for coming down, man.
你知道的 发生了这样的事
You know, any time something like this happens
我们把你带过来 找人谈话
we gotta bring you down, we gotta talk to people.
这都是程序上规定的 相信你他也明白
It's all the procedural bullshit. You know the drill.
-是的 我知道 -那就好
- Yeah, for sure. - Okay.
所以我想问你
So I gotta ask you...
就没有什么不平常的事发生吗？
nothing seemed out of the ordinary? Not a thing?
我知道听起来有些疯狂
Uh, I know it sounds crazy,
但我四处拜访了一下
but, you know, I was making the rounds,
然后就去上厕所 我没听见什么 然后就回来了
I went to the bathroom. I didn't hear anything. I come back.
就这样
That's it.
你认识这些家伙吗？
You know these guys?
一个叫迈克尔迪米奇
That guy's a Michael Dimitriu
另一个叫埃迪帕帕加斯
and another guy's Eddie Papastratos.
是一些不重要的罪犯 但我就是想知道你认识他们吗
They're small time criminals, but I wanted to know if you knew them.
-为什么？ -我只是想校对一下 没别的
- Yeah, why? - I was just checking, that's all.
我没跟他们说过话 如果你知道...
I mean I haven't spoken to them in a while, you know, if--
所以...
SO...
我相信他们跟这事没关系
you know, I'm sure they had nothing to do with this
-如果这是你说的话 -我没这样说
- if that's what you're saying. - I didn't say that.
没事
But okay.
好吧 那...
Okay, so,
你还要问别的问题呢还是就这样？
you have any more questions or is that it?
你说只有一个人
You said that there was only one guy, right,
-闯进去了 就是劫匪 对吧？ -不不不 我没这样说
- who broke in, the robber? - No no, I didn't.
我没看见任何人 所以
You know, I didn't see anyone, so.
嗯
Huh.
我们这有个视频
You know we got this video here
就在钱柜附近
and, uh, near the money room
正前方有个戴着面具的人
right before the guy with the ski mask
他发现了并毁了这摄像机
looks up and he smashes the surveillance camera,
看起来他好像在跟谁说话
it's like he's talking to someone.
然后他向上看
Then he looks up
好像是有人告诉他这里有个摄像机
like someone told him where the camera was.
还真是不可思议啊
It's the weirdest thing.
我已经说过了 我没看见任何人
Like I told you, I didn't see anyone, so.
是啊 你已经说过几次了
Yeah, you said that already-- a few times.
-是啊 -好吧
- Yeah. - Okay.
好吧 你什么都不知道
Okay, you don't know nothing.
那这算是结束了？
Okay, are we good?
是的 我们结束了
Yeah yeah yeah. We're done.
那就好
Okay, great.
我感谢过你救了我的命 对吧？
I thanked you for saving my life, right?
-是啊 -那就好
- Yeah. - Okay, good.
但是这不意味着
But that don't mean for a goddamn second
我不会揍扁你
that I won't hesitate to drag your ass in
如果我发现你对我撒谎了的话
if I find out you've been lying to me about all this shit.
明白了吗？
Do you understand?
知道了
Yeah, I got it.
那就好
All right, we're cool.
好了 你可以走了
Now you can go.
哇哦
Whoo!
嘿
Hey!
斯皮罗想谈一谈
Spiro wants to talk.
进来
Get in.
哟 奥兰德
Yo, Orlanda.
请坐
Please, sit down, yeah?
这里
Here.
你迟到了 嗯？
You're late, huh?
这就是我们要来的地方？
So this is where we hang out, huh?
还真是愉快的时光啊
The big time.
说吧 不要有所保留
Please, no secrets.
把你们的包和我们的放在一起
Put your bag down right next to ours.
好的
It's cool.
八百万 都在这了
Eight mill, all there.
纯可卡因呢？
The coke pure?
为什么人们老是问这问题呢？
Why do people always ask that, huh?
你以为在拍电影？肯定不是啊
It's the movies, yeah? Of course.
干净的钱？
Clean?
当然
Of course.
看来你很认真啊
Now you must have serious financing
迈克你竟然让这人代替了吉米
for Mike to make you his partner instead of Jimmy.
-对吧？ -是的
- Right? - Yeah well,
吉米不会再参与进来了
listen, Jimmy ain't a part of this no more.
明白吗？
Okay?
知道了
Okay.
数一下
Let's count it.
那我们现在就再等等 嗯？
And now we wait, huh?
那可是一大笔钱啊
It's a lot of money to count.
克里斯克里斯塔
Christo Christara.
哇 你最近可不常来了 嗯？
Wow, you've been through a lot lately, huh?
是他妈的有些时日了
Some couple of fucking days.
我们有事找你
We got something for you.
我们的客人在哪呢？
Where's-- where's our special guest?
有人知道我们的客人在哪吗？
Anybody know where our special guest is?
-在拉尿 -拉尿？
- Taking a piss. - He's taking a piss?
是的 拉尿
He's taking a piss.
嘿 他竟然在拉尿
Hey, he's taking a piss.
好吧
Okay, so.
在你告诉我 你把从帝国那抢来的钱藏哪之前
Before you tell me where the money from the robbery is in the Bronx--
你他妈的先告诉我你为什么要
and you're gonna fucking tell me, which is the only reason
我们不马上把你脑袋拧下来的理由
we don't bash your fucking head in right now--
不过在这和之前 我要你见个人
but before you do, there's somebody I want you to meet
那人跟我说你不希望 我参与那抢劫案
who's been telling me about a robbery you didn't want to include me in on.
斯皮罗 听着
Spiro, listen,
我不知道你在说什么 好吗？
I don't know what you're talking about, okay?
嘿 我知道我在说什么
Hey, I understand. I understand! That's why I'm saying
我只是想让你先见个人
I just want you to meet somebody first.
这他妈的不是什么难事
It's not a big fucking deal!
现在他来了 我们不需要等了
And here he comes. We don't have to wait any longer.
我们特殊的客人
Our fucking special guest--
吉米回来了 死里逃生
Mr. Jimmy back from the fucking dead.
不可置信 对吧？
Unbelievable, right?
下次你要杀谁 他妈的请确认你真的杀死了他
Next time you want to kill somebody, make sure you fucking kill him!
克里斯 你现在要怎么办？
How you doing now, Christo, huh?
你他妈的现在去把属于我的钱拿来
Now go get my fucking money.
两个？
Two?
是的
Yeah.
埃迪帕帕加斯是今晚工作吗？
Eddie Papastratos working tonight?
今晚不来
Not tonight.
那他的朋友克里斯波特米呢？
How about his friend, Chris Potami?
你们是谁？
Who's asking?
警察
Cops.
要点菜吗？
How about some menus?
甜心 没事的 我们真是警察
Naw, it's all right, honey. We really are cops though.
如果可以的话我们想看看 埃迪的柜子
If it's okay, we'd like to look in Eddie's locker.
没问题吧？
Is that all right?
艾莱尼 你来一下
Eleni, come here.
这些家伙说他们是警察
These guys say they're cops
还想看埃迪的柜子
and they want to look in Eddie's locker or something.
警察 两个都是吗？
You're cops, the two of you?
-真的吗？ -是的 小姐
- Those real? - Yes ma'am.
-是啊 -他做了什么？
- Yeah. - What'd he do?
我们希望他没做
Well, we're hoping nothing.
好吧 跟我来吧
All right then. Come on.
-跟你走吗？ -是的
- Just follow you? - Yep.
去吧 随你们想干什么
Go ahead, do what you want.
-哪个？ -中间那个
- Which one? - Middle.
-没问题吧？ -嗯哼
- It's okay? - Mmm.
如果你在里面找到个女孩子的话 就交给我处理
Find any shit about another girl in there, you hand it over to me.
好的 知道了
Yeah, you got it.
该死的方法
No goddamn way.
哇哦
Wow.
是八百万
Is eight.
八百万
Eight million.
都在这
It's all there.
这400块钱
Here's 400 extra.
是你们的
It's yours.
好了
Okay,
你们可以走了
you can go now.
-你在说什么？ -起来吧
- What are you talking about? - Stand up,
转身然后出去
turn around and walk out that door.
你他妈的在说什么？
What the fuck are you talking about?
不难理解啊
It's not hard.
起来
Stand up...
转身
turn around
-然后出去 -等下 先坐着
- and walk out the door. - Sit still.
你他妈的在说什么 出去？
What the fuck are you talking about, walk out?
-哇哦哇哦 不要激动 -我说了转身
- Whoa whoa whoa, relax relax. - I said turn around,
-然后出去 明白了吗？ -发生什么事了？
- and walk out the door, yeah? - What's going on?
-转身然后出去 -好的好的 你冷静
- Turn around and walk out the door. - Okay, chill.
把枪放下 把枪放下
Put the gun down, put the gun down.
-要我帮你们的忙吗？ -发生什么事了？
- I said do yourself a favor. - What the fuck is going on?
出去
Walk out the door.
-出去！ -你他妈的向我嘴巴里开枪？
- Go! - You shot me in my fucking mouth?
出去 他妈的给我滚出去
Get the fuck out! Go now!
滚出去
Get the fuck out of here now!
-快给我滚出去 -你他妈的是认真的吗？
- Get the fuck out now! - Are you fucking serious, huh?
-还他妈的朝我嘴巴里开枪 -*上帝啊
- In the fucking mouth! - Heavenly Father
*救救这些人吧
Save the people
*救救他们的灵魂
Save their souls
-*救救我们的父亲 -快点快点
- Save our father... - Come on, come on, come on.
*救救我们的母亲
Save our mother...
该死的
Oh! Fuck!
-*救救这些人 -他妈的把钱还给我们
- Save the people... - Get us our fucking money!
*救救他们的灵魂
Save their souls...
埃迪？
Eddie?
结束了
It's over.
我来跟他说
I'll talk to him.
埃迪 埃迪
Eddie, Eddie.
埃迪 埃迪 埃迪
Eddie, Eddie, Eddie.
检察官把半数以上的印度人抓了起来
My DA's got half the Italian mob on lockdown,
我们也很好奇在帝国消失的钱
my lieutenant's wondering how half the missing Empire money
怎么会有一半会出现在 哥伦比亚毒品商人手上
landed in the lap of some mid-level Colombian cocaine dealer
而且我觉得 你和你朋友知道另一半在哪
and I'm thinking you and your friend know where the other half is.
所以在你走之前
So before I let you go--
很不幸的我不得不
and unfortunately I have to--
问你两个问题 埃迪
I've got two questions for you, Eddie:
克里斯在哪？
Where's Chris?
钱在哪？
And where's the money?
克里斯 克里斯 发生什么事了？
Chris, Chris, what is going on?
我现在是认真的 你必须告诉我发生了什么
I'm being serious right now. You need to tell me what happened.
该死的 爸爸
Shit, my father.
-走吧 -克里斯 我是认真的
- Fuck, come on. - Chris, I'm being serious.
你必须看着我 然后告诉我发生了什么
You need to look at me and you need to tell me what's going on.
不管发生了什么 你都要去看那雕像 明白吗？
Whatever happens, you check the fucking statue, okay?
-一定要去看那雕像 -克里斯 什么？
- You check the statue. - Chris, what?!
-钱就在雕像下面 -克里斯！
- The money's in the fucking statue. - Chris!
克里斯
Chris.
Chris!
克里斯
Yo, Chris!
你他妈的在这干什么？
What the fuck are you doing here?
他们知道了一切 一切都知道了
They know everything. They fucking know everything.
-什么？谁？ -警察
- What, who? - The cops know everything.
-他们找到了地图 -所以你他妈的就来找我？
- They got the fucking map. - You come to me?!
-该死的 -那你认为我要怎么办？
- Oh fuck. - What do you want me to do?
兄弟 没那么简单的
It ain't that easy, bro. It ain't that easy.
你还跟我说吉米死了
Hey, you told me Jimmy was dead.
他妈的他哪里死了 他还活着
He ain't fucking dead, Eddie! He's alive.
你说什么？ 可我亲眼看见迈克把他杀了
What are you talking about? I saw Mike kill him with my own eyes.
他没死 明白吗？ 我们他妈的都被骗了
Well, he ain't dead, okay, and we're fucked!
我的钱都没了 就在刚才
All my money's gone. All my money's gone right now.
-我需要一些钱 -你需要钱？
- I need some money. - Oh, you need some money?
-我需要一些钱 -我还以为你说警察需要呢
- I need some money, ple-- - I thought you said the cops need it?
-你现在他妈的给我滚蛋 -你最好现在就给我钱
- Now get the fuck outta here! - You gotta give me that money
我知道钱就在这附近的地方
right now. I know it's in here somewhere, bro.
-我不想再做别的事 -我他妈的
- I don't want to do anything. - I'm not gonna give you
不会给你一分钱 埃迪
any fucking money, Eddie!
我现在不想做什么 明白吗？ 不要让我
I don't want to do anything right now, okay? Don't make me do
-对你做一些混蛋的事 -你他妈的在做什么
- anything I don't want to fucking do. - The fuck are you doing?
不要逼我做这样的事 好吗？
Don't make me fucking do anything right now, okay?
我他妈的现在很紧张 快告诉我钱在哪？
I'm so fucking serious right now. Just show me where it is right now.
他妈的告诉我钱在哪 好吗？
Just show me where the fucking money is, okay?
-我的钱是要留给我的家人的 -我他妈的很抱歉
- My money's for my family. - I'm fucking sorry!
-留给他们买房子的 -我不想这样的
- For my parents to get a house. - I don't want it all!
用那些钱你他妈的可以买 很多房子
You could buy 10 fucking houses with that fucking money!
那我呢？
What about me, okay?
不要以为我不敢做
Don't think I won't do it.
他妈的不要以为我不会开枪
Don't think I won't fucking shoot!
该死的
Oh fuck!
-该死的 -嘿 爸
- Fuck. - Hey, Pop.
埃迪 起来
Get up, Eddie.
-要不然下一个杀的就是你 埃迪 -该死的
- The next one kills you, Eddie. - Fuck.
-下一个死的就是你 现在给我起来 -他妈的该死的
- The next one kills you. Now get up! - Aw fuck!
-嘿 爸爸 冷静 -快给我起来
- Hey, come on, Pa. - That's it, get up.
起来 给我起来
Come on, get up.
-该死的 -爸爸 求你了 不要这样
- Fuck! - Come on, Dad, please.
先生 那该死的警察就要来了
The fucking cops are coming, Mr. P.
是啊 他们现在就来 现在就在这了
Yes, here they come. Yes, they're coming.
-警察要来了 爸爸 我们快走吧
The cops are coming, Dad, come on.
是啊 他们来了 你现在开心了
Yeah, they're coming now. You happy now?
-爸 求你了 -闭嘴
- Come on, Pop. Come on. - Shut up!
你就呆在这
You stay right here.
-好 好 -该死的
- Yeah yeah. - Aw fuck.
先生 警察已经来了
The cops are coming, Mr. P.
-我知道他们来了 -该死的警察
- Yes, here they come. - The fucking cops.
-操你妈的 -你他妈的不要动 埃迪
- Fuck! - Don't you fucking move, Eddie!
一切都结束了
This is over now.
-一切都结束了 你不要动 -不许动 不许动
- This is over! You stay right there! - Freeze freeze!
-不许动 -把枪放下
- Don't you move! - Put that gun down!
-不 他是我爸爸 他是我爸爸 -不许动 快把枪放下
- No, he's my father, my father! - Freeze freeze, you put that gun down!
我说把枪放下
I said drop that gun.
把枪放下
D"掳P the gun!
-求你了 -我说了放下枪
- Please. - I said put it down.
-求你了 不要 -把枪放下
- Please, come on. - Put it down!
-求你了 好吗？ -一切都结束了
- Please, okay? - It's over now.
都清楚了
It's clear!
嘿 该死的 你们小心
Hey, you fuck! Hey, you fuck, hey, watch it!
不许动 不许动
Off off, hands off! Hands off him, hands off.
嘿 他是我爸爸 你们不要伤害他
Hey, he's my father, don't you fucking hurt him!
嘿 克里斯 不要 冷静一下
Hey hey hey, Chris, no! Hey, take it easy.
-哦 该死的 -该死的 强森
- Ow! Fuck! Ow! - Hey! Fuck, Johnson!
冷静 冷静
Take it easy, take it easy.
该死的
Oh fuck!
没事的 克里斯 没事的
It's okay. It's okay, Christo.
一切都结束了
It's over now.
-对不起 爸爸 很抱歉 -一切都结束了
- I'm sorry, Father. I'm sorry. - It's over now.
-该死的 抱歉 爸 -我们走吧
- Fucking-- I'm sorry, Pop. - Let's go.
我他妈的很抱歉
I'm fucking-- I'm fucking sorry.
-没事的 克里斯 -我现在很混乱
- It's okay, Christo. - I fucked up.
一切都结束了
It's over now.
该死的 我该死
Ah fuck. I fucked up.
是啊 的确 克里斯
Yeah. Yeah, you did, Chris.
你的确该死
Yeah, you did.
嘿 老板 还有一些钱下落不明
Hey, boss, still got a lot of money unaccounted for here.
你不知道吗
And don't you know it.
你认为他们会说吗？
You think your boy's gonna talk?
是啊 我相信他会良心发现的
Yeah. I think he'll come to his senses.
联邦调查局说
The FBI said today
原本职责为保护这些钱的人
that the man whose job it was to protect the money
却偷了它 这人就是克里斯波特米提斯
stole it: Christos Potamitis.
我们破坏了他的假期
We spoiled his vacation where he's been
当时他一下午都在晒日光浴
sunning himself by the pool most of the afternoon.
就算是我我也会
It was a matter of me trying to get
把流向我的袋子捡起来的
a bag to come to me.
房东说他很好奇
The building's landlord said he was amazed
小偷怎么可以从屋顶爬过呢
the burglars could get through the roof.
这屋顶
Uh, we specifically made this roof
我们可是用的钢结构
to have steel construction because we wanted to have
就是为了确保房子的安全
the security in there.
就感觉好像有白花花的钱 从我面前落下一样
Just dollar signs, you know, coming at me.
你知道这种感觉吗？ 就好像置身于钱堆里一样
You know? "Here we are."
联邦调查局说这案件还没结束
More arrests are expected says the FBI,
还有1.1干万元的缺口
as is recovery of the 11 million,
现在还下落不明
which is still missing.
这些钱就这样没了？
And the money still to this day is gone?
-是的 -无影无踪了？
- That's correct. - Vanished?
无影无踪了
Just vanished.
-蒸发了吗？ -蒸发了
- Into thin air? - Into thin air.
就像从钱柜里消失一样
The way it disappeared out of the money room,
它现在也从我们手中消失了
it disappeared out of our hands.
看起来你还有话说
You looked like you were about to say something.
没有了
No.
好吧
Okay.
*好像从未下雨
Seems it never rains
*在加利福尼亚南部
In southern California
*我好像听说过
Seems I've often heard
*这样的话
That kind of talk before
*但是他们也不会给你警告
But, girl, don't they warn ya
*就这样倾泻而下
It pours
*倾泻而下
Man, it pours
*失业后的我疯狂了
Out of work, I'm out of my head
*不自重的我失业了
Out of self-respect, I'm out of bread
*没有人爱我 没有人养育我
I'm underloved, I'm underfed
*我要回家
I wanna go home!
*加利福尼亚从未下雨
It never rains in California
*但是他们也不会给你警告
But, girl, don't they warn ya
*就这样倾泻而下
It pours
*倾泻而下
Man, it pours
*你能让他们回家吗
Will you tell the folks back home
*我差点就成功了
I nearly made it?
*我努力了 但却无人知道
Had offers, but don't know
*我该怎么做
Which one to take
*求你告诉我
Please
*不要告诉他们你是怎么找到我的
Don't tell them how you found me
Don't tell 'em how you found me
*让我休息一会
Gimme a break
Give me a break
*好像加利福尼亚从未下雨
Seems it never rains in southern California
*似乎我听过这样的话
Seems I've often heard that kind of talk before
*加利福尼亚从未下雨
It never rains in California
*但是他们也不会给你警告
But, girl, don't they warn ya
*他们就那样倾泻而下
It pours
*就那样倾泻而下
Man, it pours.